<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>GameFi Archives | Algobitz</title>
	<atom:link href="https://algobitz.com/category/gamefi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://algobitz.com/category/gamefi/</link>
	<description>Blockchain, NFT, Web 3 Development Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 08:31:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://algobitz.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cropped-algobitz-logo-03-32x32.png</url>
	<title>GameFi Archives | Algobitz</title>
	<link>https://algobitz.com/category/gamefi/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Why Web3 games should focus on Sustainability?</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/why-web3-games-should-focus-on-sustainability/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/why-web3-games-should-focus-on-sustainability/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 08:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=18986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Web3 games have recently gained pace with several GameFi projects going live on daily basis. The ongoing situation is a</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/why-web3-games-should-focus-on-sustainability/">Why Web3 games should focus on Sustainability?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web3 games have recently gained pace with several <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="https://algobitz.com/gamefi-101-how-to-enhance-your-gaming-experience-while-making-money/">GameFi</a></strong></span> projects going live on daily basis. The ongoing situation is a good opportunity to observe and re-evaluate the essence of Web3 gaming. For quite some time, we’ve analyzed many well-established gaming companies launching fabulous projects on Web3, in parallel to new companies entering the Web3 ecosystem with their infant yet amazing projects, and unfortunately, we found one thing in common. Although almost all of their whitepapers included and highlighted sustainability as one of their main objectives, their workaround was primarily based on getting a massive return on their investment as early, after the game goes live, as possible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eventually, this way of thinking poses threat to the reliability of many good game prospects for the long and even mid-level term. The volatility of most cryptocurrencies on which GameFi depends creates a major obstacle to the sustainability of Web3 games. Due to the main driving force for engaging in Web3 games is to earn or trade in cryptocurrencies, there has been a lot of dependency on the volatile crypto market, which is uncontrollable for gamers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As soon as the market dips, we observed a dip in user engagement in Web3 games. As a result, many companies who are self-funded or looking forward to upcoming funding round, face negative consequences. These instances also prove that long-term goals of designing a good game economy, may also not be worthy of putting effort, due to such an underlying system crumbling the sustainability of the game. The fact that the focus of a major section of players is on the value of their digital assets in a game puts up two concerns: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there is a sudden impact on the Web3 ecosystem, would that start a panic amongst those players and eventually initiates an exodus from the game?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the game&#8217;s digital assets can only be traded in a particular cryptocurrency, then what would keep those players engaged in the game if its value drops at a certain point?</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These issues act as catalysts for speculation, and in time they give a higher but unsustainable, investment return to the players. Practically, you can’t eliminate them from any game because that will be a blow to the major attraction for the players to try a Web3 game and stay in its environment. Till the time this strategy is working well, only those games that compromise on sustainability against growth will flourish.</span></p>
<h2><b>How can Web3 Games become sustainable?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Suppose the primary ground for gamers to be in the game is the speculative value of their digital assets. In that case, no matter how well-fabricated the in-game economy is, the game will not be sustainable. The establishment of sustainability in a gaming environment can only be achieved if the driving force of players changes from &#8216;this is a game where you play to make money&#8217; to &#8216;this is a game with great gameplay experience, you play to have fun, and you *can* also earn or get rewarded through that for your time and efforts&#8217;. If players come to the game with such an objective, then they won’t flee the game in the case of a drop in their digital asset value. Certain ways could help achieve these objectives, and hence sustainability, however, they all have their own challenges.</span></p>
<h3><b>Proper Utilization of Early Investment</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What we need to understand is that early players in a game are not particularly aiming at the gameplay, they are actually looking to crowdfund the game developers for the growth of the game. Since the early players are actually the investors, they expect the game to be established to attract more players who will be spending money to supply profits to the early investors. Hence, most games have a framework to sell securities with utility elements, like virtual real estate that will provide passive income to the holders based on the activity performed on them by players; as well as Initial Coin Offerings and NFT presales where buyers expect to sell those assets later. This framework has some clear problems:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead of actual investor ideology to commit towards the growth of the game, this thinking encourages malpractices like building false hype, rug pull schemes, etc. taking unfair advantage of the absence of governance.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the target is increasing the profit on their digital assets, these early investors may leave the game if the value of their assets decreases or if the game economy crumbles.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The in-game assets should be designed around utility and must maintain their value, which creates an obstacle to bringing in new content which is a mandate for long-term sustainability.</span></li>
</ol>
<h3><b>User Generated Content</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are parallel spaces of content creators (the Earners who actually create reasons to spend on the game) and content consumers (the Spenders who spend and generate revenue for the game) in the gaming world, and blockchain technology maintains a symbiosis of transactions between them. A healthy balance between the two components is extremely necessary to incorporate sustainability into the game. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nowadays, a player can grind a digital asset in a game and trade it with any player in another game. This activity does not supply any value in the former game, because it does not give any motivation to the existing players to spend more in that game. All such grounds for players to spend in the game are already integrated by game developers in its design, however, the activities of grinding the resources and assets of a game degrade those grounds.</span></p>
<h2><b>What is next for the </b><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://algobitz.com/metaverse-gaming/">Web3 gaming</a></span><b> space?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of now, the major disadvantage for all such strategies to implement sustainability in Web3 games is that the community which engages in these games mostly comprises players who are actually involved in the blockchain domain and not the prospects who can transition from Web2 to Web3 gaming. Web3 gaming currently fuels the motivation of earning and getting high returns on early investment for the players, due to which they would naturally give precedence to short-term accomplishments over the legitimate fundamentals of sustainable growth of the gaming environment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web3 games are stuck in a deadlock where, on one hand, players think that blockchain gaming is volatile in nature and it is best to hit the jackpot as soon as possible in a game and then move on to the next game, and on the other hand, this practice is maintaining the volatility of the blockchain gaming ecosystem.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most of the Web3 games include the same defects; they grow on the same strategy and quickly wrap up after gaining profit, and successive games keep this cycle going on and on. In rare instances, some games tried to break this cycle through innovative measures for creating sustainability, however, they faced backlash and their efforts went in vain. One such example was Axie Infinity, once a crowned jewel of Web3 games, where the daily revenue sunk from approximately $8M to scarcely $10k, along with a nosedive of active accounts from 1M to 50k only. And the reason? It was a change in the strategy of its game economy to attain sustainability, that directly hit the game speculation and provoked mass abandonment of players.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We try to drop the veil for the global gaming community through our analysis and hope that players and investors will notice the negative experiences of Web3 games and dig down to find the reasons for their downfall that suddenly happened after the uprising. We expect them not to just focus on short-term growth and profits but evolve their strategies to stimulate sustainability in the Web3 games.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/why-web3-games-should-focus-on-sustainability/">Why Web3 games should focus on Sustainability?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/why-web3-games-should-focus-on-sustainability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web3 gaming: key features</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/web3-gaming-key-features/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/web3-gaming-key-features/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 12:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web 3.0]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=18207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Web3 revolution, and Web3 gaming is the next kid on the block. Web3 games are open-source online games that</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/web3-gaming-key-features/">Web3 gaming: key features</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Web3 revolution, and Web3 gaming is the next kid on the block. Web3 games are open-source online games that use blockchain technology as an underlying pillar of a game’s economy. Web gaming has a value-exchange model for gaming so that gamers can own and trade in-game assets and collectibles via unique NFTs, using game tokens or cryptocurrencies. The characteristic of the play-to-earn Web3 game economics that a player can own in-game assets draws a sheer contrast to traditional game economies, which were majorly based on a closed environment, restricting gamers from buying or selling in-game earnings for real-world value. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web3 gaming has been so far successful in providing self-sovereignty and decentralization in gaming. There are many names by which Web3 games are being adapted and promoted by gaming communities, like Play-to-Earn games, Crypto games, NFT games, etc. The assets inside the game are tangibly owned by the players as NFTs and liquid markets are established for trading these assets. Neither any central authority has governance on the Web3 gaming ecosystem, nor on the ownership of in-game assets and gameplay experiences. The players, or Gaming DAOs, manage the governance inside a Web3 game and the players have sole ownership over their earnings in this decentralized environment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us go through some fundamental features of Web3 gaming platforms:</span></p>
<h3><b>Ownership and interoperability</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While playing traditional games, players tend to lose all of their in-game assets once they decide to change the game or the gaming platform. Moreover, there was no real-world value to their digital assets. Whereas in Web3 gaming, gamers completely own their in-game assets and collectibles in the form of NFTs, which they earn through their time and efforts inside the game. This feature wraps around the concept of self-sovereignty by giving players the true ownership and interoperability of sharing their in-game digital assets across multiple platforms. That simply means that any gamer can own in-game assets on one platform and take them over to the next Web3 gaming platform of his choice, without losing their significance and value.</span></p>
<h4><b>Integrating Traditional Games</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The gaming experience is quite personalized in nature, as every gamer has his/her preferences on games, genre, characters, etc. and Web3 brings in the feature to integrate the upgraded model of old yet loved games into the metaverse and blockchain platforms, incorporating decentralization in its core to expand the domain of what players can actually do in the game. With old games mutated on the Web3 framework and running in the metaverse, players can now create their avatars there and start trading their favorite in-game collectibles and digital assets in marketplaces and take advantage of earning in cryptocurrencies or game tokens.</span></p>
<h4><b>Player-driven Game Economics</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blending the cryptocurrencies in gaming by the Play-to-Earn model of Web3 gaming makes the gaming economies more approachable, empowering the players to engage in P2E economics. The native integration between traditional MMO (Massive Multiplayer Online) game economics and P2E economics (which includes virtual assets, economic techniques and player coordination models) opens up a proper distribution framework for players. This will help in aligning incentives for gamers and game developers, along with establishing true ownership of digital assets and advancement in the game.</span></p>
<h4><b>WEB3 games negligible downtime</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web3 gaming has been able to be highly scalable and take full advantage of the attributes of decentralization, like block minting, very low maintenance cost, high data storage availability and no involvement of any centralized authority for governance, to execute autonomously and give negligible downtime to its users.</span></p>
<h4><b>Transparency in gaming</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With an established distributed framework, Web3 games are hosted on the unhackable blockchain network, thus heightening the security of the model. Another feature of blockchain technology, that is utilized in Web3 games, is DAOs (Decentralized Autonomous Organizations) which merges a high level of transparency in this model. DAOs provide the voting consensus for any modification in the game and this voting consensus can be impartially accessed by any player of the game community.</span></p>
<h2><b>Closing Thoughts on WEB3 gaming</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The prospects of Web3 gaming look encouraging in 2022 as more and more P2E games and metaverses are going live on the blockchain platform on an everyday basis. It is expected that the metaverse market will touch $800B by 2024, as this expanding virtual world and its P2E model is onboarding new users continuously in its ecosystem. As the Web3 gaming industry evolves, the demand for a massive amount of digital infrastructure and Metaverse development expertise is rising constantly.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We, at Algobitz, have recently established the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">center of excellence for Web 3.0 gaming which will bring a paradigm shift in our mission to offer </span><b>world-class Gaming solutions, animation, design and Blockchain tech</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for Global Gaming studios. The new vertical is full of talented Game Producers, Game design artists and developers, giving them access to best-in-class infrastructure and R&amp;D lab facilities, to build innovative games for Web 2.0 and Web 3.0 concurrently. To know more, check out: </span><a href="https://algobitz.com/algo-studios/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Algo Studios.</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/web3-gaming-key-features/">Web3 gaming: key features</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/web3-gaming-key-features/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inflation and its regulation in P2E Model</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/inflation-and-its-regulation-in-p2e-model/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/inflation-and-its-regulation-in-p2e-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 12:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=18086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Inflation regulation, strongest tokenomics, perfect user interface, etc are those factors that any P2E game should keep in check when</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/inflation-and-its-regulation-in-p2e-model/">Inflation and its regulation in P2E Model</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inflation regulation, strongest tokenomics, perfect user interface, etc are those factors that any P2E game should keep in check when aiming for long-term sustainability in evergrowing WEB3 space. </span></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Note that currenty there are around 300 well-established Play-to-Earn games in the market and numerous are being built daily. With billions of gamers in the global Web3 community, any new game targets to welcome a tide of gamers to bloom in the market, but a tsunami of incoming gamers sinks the economy of any game. </span></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s discuss a systematic approach toward achieving this equilibrium in any game project.</span></p>
<h2><b>Balancing the Players in the Game:</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A good number of players is a basic requirement for any game project to uphold in the market. Whether it is a newly launched game or any already-established game, if it does not get a sufficient number of players at any point in time, it will collapse. Many game companies assume that if they make their game free to play, they will attract a large number of players to their game, and this may work for many games, however, this approach is not feasible for the <a href="https://algobitz.com/play-to-earn-gaming/">Play-to-Earn</a> model. Since the most attractive feature of P2E gaming is trading in-game rewards like NFTs, tokens, etc., on blockchain platforms, a large number of players sharing the same motive would bring out aggressive inflation in the game economy, and ultimately it will fall to pieces.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One may think that we can restrict the rewards for free players and that should do. However, when thousands of free players create inflation on those restricted rewards, that would sum up to be catastrophic for the game economy. Moreover, the existence of bots that squeeze out the resources of a game, is another critical issue. When the negligible impact of each bot on the game resources accumulates with the impacts of thousands of bots, it crumbles down the game economy at once. Another common misconception is to let players enter the game for free but not allow them to get any rewards, but that is faulty from the core because this concept would be the replica of traditional pay-to-play games where profit is the priority and gameplay for free players is compromised.</span></p>
<h4><b>Resolution</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">: </span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some brilliant minds of <a href="https://algobitz.com/nft-games-create-serious-hype-among-developers-with-advent-of-web-3/">GameFi</a> and the Play-to-Earn domain have come up with key alterations in the P2E model, which would shield the game economy from the negative impact of having too many players. There has been a slight change in the framework according to which the free players would get unrestricted access to the game but restricted ability to trade in-game assets to the blockchain market. The revised structure would not impact the incoming flow of gamers in the game but would create a safeguard against the negative impacts. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few games, like BattleMancers, allow free players to enter the game and earn rewards, just like any player with an initial investment in the game (premium player) would get, but either they’re unable to trade outside the game, or they’d need to transact with the premium players or buy something from the game backend, to enable the trade of their assets outside the game. As a result, the gameplay is not compromised at all; both free and premium players stay competitive and have fun, however, the final motive of taking in-game assets on the global blockchain market to trade, requires the free players to compensate the premium players or the game developers in some way or the other.</span></p>
<h2><b>An Experience of Being Recognized</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A majority of Web3 gaming projects are focused on making profits. They try to sell as many assets, NFTs, or tokens as possible before and after the game launch because they have short-term objectives for their game. Their game is not intended to create an unforgettable gameplay experience for the players, but to extract maximum profit in the first phase of the game itself. This immense drive designed by the game company causes inflation in the game economy. The players, who took the bait and invested in the initial phase of the game, found shrinking returns and reduced prices of their investment amount. These players invested with the thought of being recognized in the next phases of the game, which is a core driving need for any player. Now, what happens is that such a practice disturbs the trust of the community and the few authentic projects face the after-effects.</span></p>
<h4><b>Resolution: </b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead of selling any tokens or assets, they should be supplied as rewards. Premium trading features, like NFT minting, etc. can be limited to initial investors only, whereas the gameplay is identical for everyone. Through this strategy, the initial investors will receive the profit, not the game developers. The demand for tokens can be supplied by the initial investors of the game, who will earn the token through staking or P2E, without any need for venture capital, private investors, or launchpad presales.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion: dominance against inflation</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is essential to establish mechanisms for controlling inflation in the rewards of a P2E game, as losing the value of in-game assets hampers the income potential of the initial investors. The dominance against inflation can also be achieved by controlling the number of player profiles that can mint their assets. While some NFT owners prefer staking for earning tokens, others prefer renting. A segment of NFT owners may prefer listing their NFTs on platforms like Opensea, while other segments may either prefer spending their NFTs in the game for upgrading their gameplay experience or hold them as collectibles.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any game based on the P2E model can sustain only if a small number of players are engaged to trade their rewards. When the bulk population of the game engages in selling their in-game assets, then it’s the onset of failure for the game economy because this very activity directly exploits the major premise of the game, i.e. gameplay and fun.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/inflation-and-its-regulation-in-p2e-model/">Inflation and its regulation in P2E Model</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/inflation-and-its-regulation-in-p2e-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scams in GameFi projects</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/identifying-scams-in-gamefi-projects/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/identifying-scams-in-gamefi-projects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 13:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=17849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Scams in Gamefi increase as the subsector notes meteoric growth. The blockchain gaming industry is one of the most prominent</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/identifying-scams-in-gamefi-projects/">Scams in GameFi projects</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scams in Gamefi increase as the subsector notes meteoric growth. The blockchain gaming industry is one of the most prominent players in the market and its prospects have never declined. </span>With the advent of blockchain-based decentralized gaming,the gaming sector started its development towards a new phase. The recent tide of new games has created a new revolution in the global community. Blockchain gaming and the incorporation of NFTs have been earnestly fascinating new players to involve in the development process, besides enjoying their favorite gameplays.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the volatility of the crypto market, GameFi has constantly stepped up and the price of its tokens is routinely increasing because of its NFT element. Investors nowadays are not attending to the need to improve the game mechanics. They are rather focused on earning profit out of reselling the in-game assets. So, analyze the marketing and technological peripheral of a project, along with the advantage its token. But this is the point where you might get tricked.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the crowd of blockchain-based projects, there is a high probability of every random one being dishonest with its offerings. One needs to be wary about the alluring promises from any <a href="https://algobitz.com/gamefi-development/">GameFi</a> project. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let&#8217;s have a look at how can we avoid such scams in gamefi and the simple strategy to identify them.</span></p>
<h2><b>How to spot a scam?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is observed that NFT games are generally wide-reaching but heavily planned on accomplishing their purpose to ransack the community. They target such investors who are not experts but novices, so they can tempt amateur investors with mesmerizing commercials. Hence, before putting the money into any project, one must be aware of the probabilities of such a trap and be wary in the following ways:</span><b></b></p>
<h3><b>1. Their Team:</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If someone is presenting his new project in the global market, he must be someone with stockpiled knowledge and experience. Their genuine and detailed information on Internet, along with their track record of career, gives an adequate amount of reliability factor. On the other hand, when a new project&#8217;s team stays anonymous, then that is a sign of something shady. It happens regardless of the scale on which it is launched and being promoted in the market.</span><b></b></p>
<h3><b>2. Their social network:</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A quick look and analysis of the social network is asking the community to invest in the prospects of incredible success in the future. It will give you a strong hunch on its credibility. You must look out for the bunch of people following them, along with the essence of their responses in the community. This elaborates whether the community is vulnerable to being mass-scammed, or experts are involved with expert project analysis. </span><b></b></p>
<h3><b>3. Smart contract:</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With any of the easily-available online amenities, like Etherscan, BscScan, etc. you can go through the smart contracts incorporated in the project to get detailed data on the time when the project was formed, launched in the market, its users, and information on its tokens. You can check or get them checked in any community of experts, to make a calculated assessment of investing in that project.</span><b></b></p>
<h3><b>4. Network marketing:</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multi-Level Marketing (MLM) is a popular system on which a good deal of GameFi projects are framed. MLM has constantly been successful in drawing the interest of new users in the projects it has been involved in. However, MLM is the project’s only source of revenue and still they are promising huge profits to its users. Without any concrete value-added channels and structures for investors&#8217; profits, the project might be a big scam. </span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion: Beware of the scams in gamefi</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is imperative to highlight that maximum projects often start with just a white paper, an attractive website, and a token listing on a crypto exchange. Fictional employees and fake partnerships are common traps to mislead new investors. One must also try to engage in the gameplay, because if the game is not real then it might seem as a rug-pull scheme.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Algobitz provides blockchain expertise, domain knowledge and GTM strategies to start-ups looking to launch a hybrid crypto exchange. Our experienced blockchain engineers and SMEs enable you to pivot faster and smarter. We help them to acheive their business goals and penetrate the market with an impact, without falling for such scam projects.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/identifying-scams-in-gamefi-projects/">Scams in GameFi projects</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/identifying-scams-in-gamefi-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emerging Trends in GameFi</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/emerging-trends-in-gamefi/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/emerging-trends-in-gamefi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 13:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Token Development]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=14883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As all of us are well aware of what GameFi is. It refers to a mix of the most recent</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/emerging-trends-in-gamefi/">Emerging Trends in GameFi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As all of us are well aware of what GameFi is. It refers to a mix of the most recent crypto innovations with the traditional pleasure of winning rewards. Players on GameFi can lend, trade, or even rent out their earnings. Even though traditional games encourage players to collect and exchange digital assets, the value of these objects allows trading real-world money.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since GameFi has become such a well-known phenomenon, certain trends are emerging in GameFi that will keep you on your feet are: </span></p>
<h3><b>1. The Metaverse and NFTs</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NFTs are likely to become GameFi&#8217;s economic backbone. There is an irrevocable relationship between both in-game sales and the unique digital ownership rights provided by NFTs. The emergence of metaverse start-ups and finance has resulted in a three-way interdependence supporting each other. Virtual reality and augmented reality (VR/AR) devices are used in metaverse games to build immersive 3D settings where players may transact. </span></p>
<h3><b>2. More Investors</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With GameFi grabbing and maintaining interest, it appears that compelling and sophisticated games will be developed, attracting a larger number of backers and investors to the DeFi sector. Another prominent franchise that has landed a narrative in <a href="https://www.sandbox.game/en/"><strong>The Sandbox</strong></a>, where gamers will be able to enter a simulated zombie world, is The Walking Dead. The world seems to be liking the integration of Crypto, Gaming and NFT world, but there is no doubt in saying that GameFi space is ready to explode in the coming future.</span></p>
<h3><b>3. Cloud Gaming gaining Popularity</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cloud gaming refers to the process of playing video games on servers located remotely in data centres. On a PC or console, there is no need to download and install games. Instead, to transmit gaming data to an app or browser downloaded on the remote host, streamers require a steady internet connection. The game is processed and played on a distant server, yet everything is visible with interactions on your device. It&#8217;s the same as Netflix or any other streaming service. The only exception is that the server providing the video stream may also monitor and respond to your inputs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Due to its various benefits and cost redundancy, cloud gaming is an excellent choice. It has been emerging and will reach heights in the coming future. The fundamental feature that makes cloud gaming appealing to those looking to migrate from traditional gaming is cross-platform syncing.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The number of blockchain-based gaming dApps is growing at a significant rate. These tendencies, taken together, point to an ecosystem that is rapidly evolving and improving.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, GameFi and blockchain gaming will have a promising future in the coming years. Many new blockchain games will be released, and there is a largely untapped market of gamers who might switch from traditional games to <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://algobitz.com/play-to-earn-gaming/"><strong>blockchain games</strong></a></span>. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/emerging-trends-in-gamefi/">Emerging Trends in GameFi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/emerging-trends-in-gamefi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Web3 Gaming Forecast &#124; Play-to-Earn Games</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/a-forecast-on-web3-gaming/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/a-forecast-on-web3-gaming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 13:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web 3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=17324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Web3 gaming has inclined the worldwide community to invest and expose its potential. The P2E model is focused on incentivizing</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/a-forecast-on-web3-gaming/">Web3 Gaming Forecast | Play-to-Earn Games</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Web3 gaming has inclined the worldwide community to invest and expose its potential. The P2E model is focused on incentivizing the time and efforts that a player invests into a game in the real world. The old structure and lack in real world value are the major reasons for exhaustive gameplay in the past. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The global gaming community gets appreciated for their inputs and earnings in the game as it brings out monetary value and reputation. The gamers can now transform their in-game collectibles like costumes, weapons, avatars, real estate, arts, etc. into NFTs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here, blockchain trading will be enabled benefitting gamers in the Web3 gaming world. Thus, with the advent of such a widely spread network and reputation, a player can produce his regular income by gaming.</span></p>
<h2>GameFi&#8217;s Boost:</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A sledgehammer market of almost $300 Billion is revolving around <a href="https://algobitz.com/gamefi-development/">GameFi</a>. The scope of innovating better and more engaging games every day has empowered the developers to bring out their best. South Asia and other parts of the world are experiencing additional players entering this domain to make it their livelihood. It is possible because of the perfect recipe of gaming and blockchain-based finance, known as DeFi. It generates a better way of income opportunities every day for its users, without compromising on their desire to play.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the distributed ledger of blockchain, crypto games make their players verified owners of digital assets for income generation. Incorporating DeFi tools generate income while playing provides financial incentives for the in-game development of assets. The players earn crypto gaming tokens as income by staking the digital assets to get crypto and other rewards.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain also brings forth the establishment of <a href="https://algobitz.com/what-is-a-dao/">DAO</a> to enable voting rights for Web3 gamers to decide the future of the game. They can create and sustain governance in the digital environment and work together to grow it smoothly. These abilities also reward them in a financial aspect by changing the rewards for the activities in the game.</span></p>
<h2>Conclusion:</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The core pillars of Web3 games &#8211; Blockchain technology, P2E structure, asset ownership, and NFTs &#8211;  are the perfect formula for unimaginable prospects. It is reaching new heights with every passing day. A majority of players are now getting income opportunities in the nascent stage of Web3 gaming. It is not far-fetched to believe that we have just scratched the surface of the iceberg with many prospective applications of GameFi awaiting to be discovered.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/a-forecast-on-web3-gaming/">Web3 Gaming Forecast | Play-to-Earn Games</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/a-forecast-on-web3-gaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain Gaming Sector aka GameFi posts rapid growth</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/blockchain-gaming-sector-aka-gamefi-posts-rapid-growth/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/blockchain-gaming-sector-aka-gamefi-posts-rapid-growth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 06:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=14997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain gaming or gamefi is one of the most talked-about things in the crypto world, and it&#8217;s rising in popularity</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/blockchain-gaming-sector-aka-gamefi-posts-rapid-growth/">Blockchain Gaming Sector aka GameFi posts rapid growth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain gaming or gamefi is one of the most talked-about things in the crypto world, and it&#8217;s rising in popularity and use. GameFi means making money out of the gaming experience. It is a mix of the words &#8220;game&#8221; and &#8220;finance.&#8221; Of course, generating money playing online games is nothing new, but with the debut of GameFi, gamers have access to an abundance of new prospects thanks to blockchain technology and decentralized financing (DeFi).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GameFi&#8217;s origins date back to 2013, when bitcoin was not as widespread as it is now, but game developers had already begun to adopt it into their productions. For example, the game Bombermine. However, the GameFi sector grew slowly until 2021, when it made a breakthrough. The introduction of NFT and DeFi was the reason. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By 2020, GameFi projects started showing up on the crypto market in the form that we know them now — blockchain games in which users may earn tokens and in-game digital assets that can be sold on the resale market in addition to entertainment and collecting in-game objects. The <a href="https://algobitz.com/web3-gaming-key-features/">GameFi</a> sphere has a multi-million dollar fanbase thanks to this concept, which is growing steadily.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The summer of 2021 is known as the &#8220;summer of NFT&#8221; or gamification as multiple cryptocurrency blockchain games witnessed a significant spike in the value of their tokens. Consider the Axie Infinity fever, which was followed by an AXS token surge. This Ethereum-based gaming platform once generated above $ 800 million in revenue in 30 days, making it the frontrunner in this indication among all DeFi protocols.</span></p>
<h2><b>The future of blockchain gaming</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to <a href="http://naavik.co/digest/industry-china">Naavik</a> and <a href="https://www.bitkraft.vc/gaming-industry-market-size/">BITKRAFT</a> Ventures, the blockchain gaming market will increase at a 100% CAGR from $1.5 billion in 2021 to $50 billion in 2025. It is ten times the traditional gaming industry&#8217;s predicted CAGR i.e. 10%.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The distinctions between GameFi and traditional gaming could become further blurred depending on how traditional gaming companies implement blockchain technology. For example, ATRI (by video game developer Atari), Netmarble, and WEMIX have all launched or are planning to issue their crypto coins (by South Korean gaming company WeMade). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GameFi&#8217;s fair value and the number of users are expected to skyrocket. Overall, GameFi and blockchain gaming will have a bright future soon. Many new blockchain games will be released, and there is a largely untapped market of gamers who might potentially migrate from traditional games to blockchain games. </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/blockchain-gaming-sector-aka-gamefi-posts-rapid-growth/">Blockchain Gaming Sector aka GameFi posts rapid growth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/blockchain-gaming-sector-aka-gamefi-posts-rapid-growth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Investment guide to some incredible Gamefi projects</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/investment-guide-to-some-incredible-gamefi-projects/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/investment-guide-to-some-incredible-gamefi-projects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 08:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=14993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Investment in traditional assets is left far behind, it is the era of blockchain investment now. GameFi and play-to-earn (P2E)</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/investment-guide-to-some-incredible-gamefi-projects/">Investment guide to some incredible Gamefi projects</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment in traditional assets is left far behind, it is the era of blockchain investment now. GameFi and play-to-earn (P2E) projects and protocols have been rapidly growing in leaps and bounds. These demonstrates significant advantages over conventional gaming and providing players with the unique potential to experience the benefits of their involvement. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GameFi incorporates features from developing blockchain sectors such as DeFi, NFTs, and decentralized gaming. This technology enables an individual to perceive in-depth knowledge of traditional gaming. NFTs, for example, have long been an integral part of GameFi, mostly functioning as in-game characters or assets. GameFi is dictating the crypto universe these days, handling billions of dollars each year. Apart from technologically reinventing the game industry, it is also positioning itself as a tremendously valuable investment opportunity.</span></p>
<p><strong>How to choose a <a href="https://algobitz.com/gamefi-development/">Gamefi</a> project from investment perspective?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without a question, the most essential feature to look for in crypto-based projects is security. Only invest through well-known and reliable launchpads after verifying the credibility of the initiative&#8217;s social media. Choosing a promising and trustworthy IDO (a source of gaining funds from retail investors) project is the first step towards a profitable investment venture. Unfortunately, some fraudulent projects continue to exist to defraud investors, so keep an eye out for them. </span></p>
<p><strong>What are some emerging GameFi Projects?</strong></p>
<h3><strong>1. GamesPad</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eran Elhanani and Constantin Kogan originally established <a href="https://gamespad.io/">GamesPad</a> &#8211; serial business owners, and digital asset investors with a solid track record. The team is launching the next-generation gaming platform, which will bring together three of the most profitable industries: gaming, NFT, and the metaverse. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was founded by Eran Elhanani and Constantin Kogan, digital asset investors and speakers. They are building the next-generation gaming platform that brings together three of the most lucrative fields: gaming, nanotechnology, and the metaverse.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The project will try to appeal to retail investors by providing timely access and the option to invest, along with VCs in the best crypto gaming projects. It will serve as a one-stop-shop for all gaming, NFT, and DeFi necessities. Young founders and initiatives will be supported by the platform, which will provide full development, mentorship, and network connections in the space. GamesPad is going to be the next big thing in the GameFi and Crypto universe. It should definitely be considered as an anticipated project to invest in.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2. NTVRK</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.netvrk.co/">NTVRK</a> is a blockchain-based social VR platform that enables users to create, share, and commercialize their creations. While it is uncertain how this infrastructure will operate under stress, it does present some intriguing possibilities. Exploring the infrastructure that will support current and future GameFi projects is always a good idea. NTVRK has a market valuation of less than $80 million, despite a 37.1 % weekly price increase.</span></p>
<h3><strong>3. Pegaxy Stone (PGX)</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://pegaxy.io/">Pegaxy Stone</a> blockchain retains a dual token structure. To finish in the top three of all races, players must combine skill with strategy and deal with the game&#8217;s distinct elements. The project has a valuation of about $38 million because it is a GameFi venture with features of rental, production, and trading.</span></p>
<h2><b>Gamefi presents good investment opportunities </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gaming has emerged to be one of the finest, if not the best, applications of blockchain technology. With the rise of NFTs and the metaverse, <a href="https://algobitz.com/nft-games-create-serious-hype-among-developers-with-advent-of-web-3/">blockchain gaming</a> makes a fair investment option for users while also having fun. As a result, it can drive mass adoption far faster than other market sectors, culminating in explosive growth for GameFi projects.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/investment-guide-to-some-incredible-gamefi-projects/">Investment guide to some incredible Gamefi projects</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/investment-guide-to-some-incredible-gamefi-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impact of Combining Gaming and Finance On the Future Generation</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/impact-of-combining-gaming-and-finance-on-the-future-generation/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/impact-of-combining-gaming-and-finance-on-the-future-generation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 13:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=14988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With the advent of new technology, gaming has grown to become one of the most lucrative entertainment industries in the</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/impact-of-combining-gaming-and-finance-on-the-future-generation/">Impact of Combining Gaming and Finance On the Future Generation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">With the advent of new technology, gaming has grown to become one of the most lucrative entertainment industries in the world. If we were to track the history of gaming, the Pay 2 Win model of gaming has been largely considered the only player in the race. But, the advancements in technology have given birth to newer and more accessible forms of gaming.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The new era of gaming has proved how sometimes bringing two industries together can revolutionize the traditional ways of doing things. The most prominent example of this would be the combination of gaming and finance, usually referred to as </span><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">GameFi</span></strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">. </span></p>
<h2><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">What is GameFi?</span></strong></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">GameFi can be defined as decentralized applications (dapps) with economic incentives. While playing a game, tokens are typically awarded as prizes for undertaking game-related activities such as fighting matches, or producing digital crops. It is also known as the &#8220;play-to-earn&#8221; approach. </span></p>
<h2><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">How does GameFi Work?</span></strong></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The only parties that profited from the digital currency that was sold to players or users till now were the game developers because these assets had no actual significance. However, the power structure is changing owing to the popularity of crypto games. While traditional games have always been primarily about enjoyment, crypto games combine entertainment with the prospect of earning actual money. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">When a player purchases an asset, they are adding to the game&#8217;s economic worth. Axie Infinity, CropBytes, and Gods Unchained are some renowned crypto games that allow players to earn money by performing in-game objectives.</span></p>
<h2><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">How the Combination of Finance and Gaming will affect the Future</span></strong></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Adding to the earning aspect of GameFi, there are several other incentives to becoming a part of the GameFi community:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Players can establish ownership of in-game assets.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Its decentralized nature ensures that no single figure is in terms of setting reckless administrative decisions.</span></li>
<li><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Players cannot lose or discard any of the materials they earn during the game.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The idea of Finance and Gaming is revolutionary. If one can earn digitally by playing games, then we say that there is a scope for anything. If GameFi takes off, the future generation will reap its benefits the most. With more mainstream businesses embracing the metaverse and GameFi, this space has tremendous potential for growth.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The GameFi industry will continue to transform the existing financial sector, resulting in a new digital economy. In-game money brings endless possibilities for reaping incentives for simple tasks like finishing game stages and buying and selling avatars. The GameFi industry will continue to develop in the future, facilitating the creation of complete-game meta universes. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/impact-of-combining-gaming-and-finance-on-the-future-generation/">Impact of Combining Gaming and Finance On the Future Generation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/impact-of-combining-gaming-and-finance-on-the-future-generation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pump and Dump in GameFi</title>
		<link>https://algobitz.com/pump-and-dump-in-gamefi/</link>
					<comments>https://algobitz.com/pump-and-dump-in-gamefi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 10:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://algobitz.com/?p=14982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The widespread acceptance of cryptocurrencies, and the scope of the crypto market, which is substantial enough for people to make</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/pump-and-dump-in-gamefi/">Pump and Dump in GameFi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The widespread acceptance of cryptocurrencies, and the scope of the crypto market, which is substantial enough for people to make millions off of it, will inevitably draw those with malicious motives. Based on the decentralized nature of cryptocurrencies, immoral behaviours are familiar to consumers, and a pump and dump is just another avenue for malevolent operators to scam gullible investors out of their hard-earned money. The other party will &#8216;pump&#8217; the market by buying considerable amounts of low-priced cryptocurrencies to unfairly boost the price of their trading platform once the newest member user puts their money. The platforms will also make it appear as if the user has access to special, secret, and highly effective trading methods, but these claims are obvious lies meant to attract the user into the scheme. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Defi-Gamefi.com is a website that helps individuals learn how to make money in the metaverse via gaming. Recently it warned new and novice traders about a type of crypto scam known as a &#8220;Pump and Dump.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Raul Meza, a writer for Defi-Gamefi.com, covers pump and dump schemes in the video. Pump and dump schemes feature fraudulent internet trading platforms having limited access or are difficult to reach through normal channels. To &#8216;join the program&#8217; or to be a share of the &#8216;pool,&#8217; new traders who are offered tailored promotions for the sites must deposit a specific sum of money. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">One major tactic to recognize unscrupulous traders is to look at their estimates for the whole crypto market and, as a result, claims for how much money people who utilize the trading platform stand to profit. The cryptocurrency market is extremely fickle, and major international events usually cause significant variations in the market capitalizations of major cryptocurrencies. Anyone claiming to be an expert on the matter is almost certainly looking to offload something to anyone who would hear them.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">The article goes on to give recommendations to anyone willing to participate in the crypto sector on how to spot and escape pump and dump scams. According to the report, one of the most telling indications that an investor is visiting a dubious trading site is if they are encouraged to take a survey or questionnaire on the platform. Questionnaires are a deceptive approach to making the platform feel trustworthy.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Finally, the post warns users not to divulge their personal information such as their name, email address, phone number, password, or any other information that can be traced back to them. If an investor is solicited by a pump and dump scam, they can report the occurrence to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) or the Federal Trade Commission right away (FTC).</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true"> According to the article, any promises of constant income and profits should be treated with a dose of scepticism since they are hoaxes meant to tempt traders misled by the allure of making quick cash, much like most things in life that are too good to be true.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com/pump-and-dump-in-gamefi/">Pump and Dump in GameFi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://algobitz.com">Algobitz</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://algobitz.com/pump-and-dump-in-gamefi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
