<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>GameFi &#8211; Fintechs.fi</title>
	<atom:link href="https://fintechs.fi/category/gamefi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://fintechs.fi</link>
	<description>Fintech &#38; Crypto News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 09:17:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-Favicon.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>GameFi &#8211; Fintechs.fi</title>
	<link>https://fintechs.fi</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nike hints At A Planned &#8216;Airphoria&#8217; NFT Sneaker Hunt On Fortnite</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/nike-hints-at-a-planned-airphoria-nft-sneaker-hunt-on-fortnite/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[irtiqa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 08:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=39524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a short video ad for its Web3 platform, Nike's logo is shown.The logo for SWOOSH is right next to the logos for Epic Games' games Unreal Engine and Fortnite.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="640" height="367" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Nike-NFT.jpeg?resize=640%2C367&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-35153" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Nike-NFT.jpeg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Nike-NFT.jpeg?resize=300%2C172&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>In a short video ad for its Web3 platform, Nike&#8217;s logo is shown.The logo for SWOOSH is right next to the logos for Epic Games&#8217; games Unreal Engine and Fortnite.</strong></p>



<p>Nike, a company that makes shoes and clothes, has hinted that it may soon drop a set of non-transferable sneaker tokens in Epic Games&#8217;s famous online game Fortnite.</p>



<p>According to Active Player, more than 242.9 million people have been playing Fortnite in the last 30 days. This could be a big chance for traditional gamers to start using Web3.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Great catch with the <a href="https://twitter.com/dotSWOOSH?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@dotSWOOSH</a> reference. <a href="https://twitter.com/FortniteGame?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@FortniteGame</a> integration would be the biggest thing that&#39;s ever happened with NFTs</p>&mdash; Jalazo.eth (@nft4dummies) <a href="https://twitter.com/nft4dummies/status/1669772911970844682?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">June 16, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Nike announced on June 16 that the &#8220;ultimate sneaker hunt&#8221; would start on June 20.</p>



<p>In a short movie that goes with it, the Fortnite logo and the Nike Air Max logo are front and center against a background of clouds moving in the sky.</p>



<p>The name of the sneaker hunt is then revealed to be &#8220;Airphoria,&#8221; and the movie ends with Nike&#8217;s logo for its web3 platform.SWOOSH next to the Unreal Engine logo from Epic Games.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">On 6.20 the ultimate Sneakerhunt begins. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f3d9.png" alt="🏙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f32c.png" alt="🌬" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/QgMyA1uXRT" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/QgMyA1uXRT</a></p>&mdash; Nike (@Nike) <a href="https://twitter.com/Nike/status/1669736937085861888?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">June 16, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>At this point, there aren&#8217;t many details, but people in the NFT community think that Nike may have made a game linked to NFT using Fornite Creative 2.0. This feature lets users build their own virtual island game maps using Fortnite assets.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p><em>“I remember that Fortnite recently launched Fortnite Creative 2.0, which has a strong self-built map mode similar to creating games on ROBLOX. I guess Nike may have used this mode to create a game. Two years ago, Nike also created a game on ROBLOX, but it was not combined with NFT[s] at that time,” noted @clone_news_cn.</em></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Even though it&#8217;s not 100% certain that NFTs will be in Airphoria,.Since SWOOSH is involved, it seems likely, and Epic Games is open to NFT games, so it could happen.</p>



<p>Lately, Nike&#8217;s NFT division has been stepping up its attempts to get into traditional gaming.</p>



<p>On June 1,.SWOOSH announced that its NFTs will be added to games made by EA Sports, which is among other things the company behind the hugely popular FIFA soccer game series. But it&#8217;s still not clear which EA Sports games will have Nike NFTs in the end.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">EA SPORTS <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f91d.png" alt="🤝" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://twitter.com/dotSWOOSH?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@dotSWOOSH</a><a href="https://t.co/hNxxdaMgRL" target="_blank">https://t.co/hNxxdaMgRL</a> <a href="https://t.co/NH8vp0fWoQ" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/NH8vp0fWoQ</a></p>&mdash; EA SPORTS (@EASPORTS) <a href="https://twitter.com/EASPORTS/status/1664287614784897028?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">June 1, 2023</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Web3 And Metaverse Fit Together For Gaming</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/how-web3-and-the-metaverse-fit-together-especially-for-gaming/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eetu Kuneinen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 09:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=36040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Using the Metaverse's tokens, users may become co-owners of the peer-to-peer digital environment known as the Metaverse. Using the Metaverse, people may add additional value, relationships, and chances to their actual life.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse.jpg?resize=640%2C360&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-30680" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse.jpg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse.jpg?resize=267%2C150&amp;ssl=1 267w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is the Metaverse?</h2>



<p>Using the Metaverse&#8217;s tokens, users may become co-owners of the peer-to-peer digital environment known as the Metaverse. Using the Metaverse, people may add additional value, relationships, and chances to their actual life. The area is adaptable and may be used for anything where connection and community produce value, including networking, business, communications, the arts, and education, in addition to gamification.</p>



<p>A user experience with little or no barriers to interoperability across games, economy, digital assets, art, and education is made feasible by the Metaverse development company. Users are empowered by its decentralized structure to produce valuable things in this new society and reap the benefits of their labor and freely trade their digital assets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What do companies need to know about the Metaverse, And why is it relevant to businesses?</h2>



<p>The Metaverse presents prospects for companies in terms of technology, the economy, and community building for their clients. Businesses may change how they relate to their clients, due to the Metaverse. Companies will be able to develop more enduring and widespread connections with consumers via the Metaverse based on shared ownership, motivation, and experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are some methods that companies may make money from the Metaverse?</h2>



<p>Some monetization strategies may have a tenuous connection to gaming. For instance, in some Metaverses, community members have established enterprises that enable them to make money by developing in-game gameplay techniques. Enterprises may also generate revenue by distributing authority and ownership to members of their communities or organizations, empowering them to establish their sub-entities and businesses and eventually enhancing the value of the larger enterprise. At this point in the Metaverse&#8217;s development, there is a lot of discovery taking place, and business models are being created, tried out, and refined quickly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Certain industries or firms stand to gain the most from the Metaverse?</h2>



<p>Due in large part to the rich gameplay features the Metaverse offers gaming communities, blockchain games, and their players have so far benefited the most from it. Due to the expanding community of builders and players who have flocked to Metaverses in little under two years, Groups of individuals from all around the globe may improve their economic and social situation due to the Metaverse communities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are the main factors influencing the growth of the Metaverse?</h2>



<p>The epidemic made it more important for individuals to interact globally, even outside social media. The purpose of the Metaverse, created to do just that, is to improve digital interactions meaningfully. In the Metaverse, there is a place for everyone, and individuals are naturally drawn to changes that will enhance their life. Previously, the development of the Metaverse was based on many of the same principles that led to the established social media sites like Myspace, Facebook, and Instagram. It has increased our ability to connect, network, and communicate while still utilizing the tools we have used.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What role does Web3 recreate in the Metaverse?</h2>



<p>Web3 refers to the stage of the internet where tokenization has made users co-owners of platforms. Contrast this with Web2, the period of the internet when people shared material but did not share ownership. Because decentralized networks provide co-ownership to all members, which is a need for the shared digital space known as the Metaverse, the Metaverse and Web3 depend on them.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What modifications are Web3 and the Metaverse making to the gaming sector?</h2>



<p>Beyond anything, we could have anticipated with Web2 or the current edition of the internet, Web3 has expanded the possibilities for gaming. It has made it possible for games that let players earn tokens as they play—tickets that have value and function in the real world—to be developed. Therefore, a player of a game in a Metaverse might acquire virtual goods with actual monetary worth, yet a player who plays Mario Kart for ten years would have nothing to show for it. To improve their standing in the Metaverse, these communities become extremely driven and motivated to generate new material, technology, and community activities.</p>



<p>Players also get co-ownership of the systems they use inside the Web3 system. They have additional motivations to further the game&#8217;s growth since they are paid for their efforts by starting companies within the Metaverse the game is housed in.</p>



<p>A variety of opportunities for people to play various games and earn money are made possible by the Metaverse, allowing users to exchange in- and inter-game goods. A player will soon be able to exchange NFT gained while playing one Metaverse game for NFT earned while playing another game, enabling them to utilize NFT across other games and participate more completely. From a player&#8217;s viewpoint, this alters the game experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are some of the trends influencing Web3 gaming? What is the future of the area?</h2>



<p>NFTS is responsible for the Web3 game development company as we know it today. The possibility of employing NFTs for purposes other than art and collectibles is the fascinating aspect of using them in the blockchain gaming industry. Players may compete in our game for resources, including tools, weapons, artifacts, and more. These NFTs come to life rather than merely being visualized.</p>



<p>Many believe decentralized Autonomous Organizations, or DAOs, will be the next big thing in this industry. A decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) is run by its entire membership (ex: members of an organization, employees in a company, etc.). These individuals cast votes on choices that affect the organization, including how money is spent.</p>



<p>Several Web3 games use DAOs (teams) as gameplay elements. Instead of a single authority seizing control and establishing the rules, DAOs provide users with great flexibility. In the end, users manage the space and have laws enacted through a smart contract. Everyone who owns a token in a DAO is a co-owner and may influence the organization&#8217;s strategic direction.</p>



<p>Gaming is a great way to introduce people to the idea of DAOs. People are compelled to comprehend the rules, the operation, and the structure of the whole system in the worlds they are playing in because of the immersive nature of gaming. If the DAO is the supporting framework for the game&#8217;s universe, then players will have to understand how it works and show how useful it is for gaming. DAOs will start to be used outside of games for things like enterprises, sports team ownership, and more once people know them and their advantages.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>62% of Axie Infinity NFT Players Leave The Game After One Year</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/62-of-axie-infinity-nft-players-leave-the-game-after-one-year/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[irtiqa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=35776</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Axie Infinity (AXS), a popular blockchain-based online video game, has reported a significant decrease in participants over the previous several months. The game's popularity fell below the level recorded for January 2021, with an average of 701,000 unique players per month during the last 30 days.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="368" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie.jpg?resize=640%2C368&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-26648" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie.jpg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie.jpg?resize=300%2C172&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Axie Infinity (AXS), a popular blockchain-based online video game, has reported a significant decrease in participants over the previous several months. The game&#8217;s popularity fell below the level recorded for January 2021, with an average of 701,000 unique players per month during the last 30 days.</strong></p>



<p>Between September 2022 and September 2021, the game based on non-fungible tokens (NFT) lost more than 62% of its average monthly unique players, falling from 1,955,000 to 739,000. The most recent results indicate the significant effect the continuous crypto market decline has had on the game. Axie Infinity has around 850,000 average monthly players as of 30 January 2021, according to statistics gathered by the gaming industry website Activeplayer.io. This was 21.3 percent more than the level recorded on September 30, 2022.</p>



<p>Compared to the number recorded on January 30, 2022, the decline in players is substantially more drastic. On that day, Axie Infinity reached its highest average monthly unique user count of 2.78 million. According to data gathered by Activeplayer.io, this constituted a fivefold increase from the previous recorded level.</p>



<p>Axie Infinity focuses on online player breeding and combat. According to the website, &#8220;you must possess at least three Axies to play the game, and these Axies cost between $250 and $500 on average.&#8221;</p>



<p>Nevertheless, some really rare Axies might cost substantially more. According to the game&#8217;s creator, the most expensive Axle ever sold cost $820,000.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New GameFi Project AniFi World&#8217;s IDO Sold Out In Two Hours</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/new-gamefi-project-anifi-worlds-ido-sold-out-in-two-hours/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 02:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=35259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Could a new GameFi project AniFi World wake the NFT game trend back in the spotlight again? ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="367" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/anifi-world.jpeg?resize=640%2C367&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-35260" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/anifi-world.jpeg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/anifi-world.jpeg?resize=300%2C172&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Could a new GameFi project AniFi World wake the&nbsp;NFT&nbsp;game trend back in the spotlight again?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>After the project opened initial DEX offering (IDO) for public sale, it sold out within two hours, totaling 210,000 BUSD ($210,000), reflecting that even In times of market turmoil, there are still some NFT games that have attracted great interest from investors.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/YEvIty7ZNof9fkAa63L2l3ZHO6RfCXlVAHj8a23S9bLYkk0bU8pO00IfFxzYPlSIcDw_aZWHdmqs0PbFwwn1c9rkJGsenfSfMA1tM0X5VJaeWvAR-isF94Yc2NzXs5rfDlAdby3X6v4VEpdrjC5tldA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>AniFi World&#8217;s IDO fundraiser yesterday was the launch of coins via Gempad, which the platform has dubbed the AniFi World project as a Diamond Tier NFT game project. The project has also received KYC identity verification and has successfully passed the Smart Contract audit.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-เก-ยวก-บ-anifi-world"><strong>What is Anifi World</strong></h2>



<p>AniFi World is an NFT Card GameFi based Smart Oracle system developed by the developer to solve the traditional Oracle problems with a concept that anyone can play.&nbsp;Either start playing games for free (free-to-play) or play to earn money.&nbsp;(play-to-earn) where anyone can earn tokens by playing the game, collecting character NFT items to sell in the secondary market.<a target="_blank" href="https://www.freedom.cards/freedom-card" rel="noreferrer noopener"></a></p>



<p>AniFi World&nbsp;aims to be one of the biggest card games on the&nbsp;Binance&nbsp;Smart Chain (BSC)&nbsp;blockchain, available to everyone for free, such as Mint NFT.&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://www.binance.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"></a></strong></p>



<p>The&nbsp;AniFi World game will use&nbsp;$ANIFI&nbsp;as the base token.&nbsp;To drive the economy and ecosystem within the entire game.&nbsp;The project also plans to use $ANIFI to integrate the game direction voting system, known as the DAO system, to truly decentralize the gamers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ANIFI coin will be listed on the Pancake Swap platform and will be available for trading simultaneously on Friday, September 2, 2022 at 11:00 p.m.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gaming Firm Xterio Raises $40M to Create Cross-platform Web3 Franchises</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/gaming-firm-xterio-raises-40m-to-create-cross-platform-web3-franchises/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 02:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=35238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Xterio to Focus on High Quality Free-to-Play Games Building Path for True Player Ownership.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/xterio.jpg?resize=640%2C360&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-35239" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/xterio.jpg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/xterio.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/xterio.jpg?resize=267%2C150&amp;ssl=1 267w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Xterio to Focus on High Quality Free-to-Play Games&nbsp;Building Path for True Player Ownership</strong>.</p>



<p>Xterio, on a mission to develop, publish and distribute high-quality mobile and Web3 games, has raised $40M funding led by FunPlus, Makers Fund, FTX Ventures, and XPLA with notable participation from HashKey, Foresight Ventures, Infinity Ventures Crypto, Matrix Partners and Animoca Brands. The platform, helmed by game executives from FunPlus, Electronic Arts, Activision Blizzard, Krafton, Jam City, NetEase and other top games brands, brings together experience from leading companies across technology, entertainment, mobile and free-to-play game design and operations.</p>



<p>Xterio’s cross-platform portfolio will focus on multiplayer games with deep, rich gaming experiences and player ownership at their core. The funding will be used to develop and publish its own games as well as partners’ games, create new world-class IP and to continue development on the Xterio platform, which will house a marketplace, social community hub and more. Multiple games are currently in development with product announcements coming this fall.</p>



<p>Xterio’s executive team builds upon decades of experience from global leaders in technology, games and entertainment. Co-Founder Jeremy Horn, formerly Vice-President of Strategy at Jam City, is a games industry veteran with deep expertise in developing and sustaining top-grossing social free-to-play games across multiple platforms. CTO Yitao Guan, who co-founded FunPlus, will oversee Xterio’s strategic and technical product focus, and CMO Darion Lowenstein, a 25+ year industry veteran, will drive marketing, publishing and licensing.</p>



<p>“At Xterio, we are building an amazing games platform that bridges how people play today with the power of Web3 for tomorrow,” said Jeremy Horn. “We believe that gameplay is enhanced by ownership, but we are most interested in creating long lasting franchises and rich gameplay experiences. We will build our games to be fun and engaging for both traditional gamers and the Web3 audience in a way that any type of player can enjoy.”</p>



<p>“Games and interactive entertainment are always at the forefront of innovation, and FunPlus has a 10-year history of innovating across web and mobile. Our belief is that Web3 has the potential to provide consumers and content creators with new ways to create, distribute and engage,” said Chris Petrovic, Chief Business Officer, FunPlus and Council Member of the Xterio Foundation. “Xterio has the right team, the right technology and the right approach to be builders in these early days of creating the next generation developer and publisher designed for the Web3 era. They understand that ultimately the entertainment value of experiences must come first to truly deliver the promise of Web3 in the long run.”</p>



<p><strong>About Xterio</strong></p>



<p>Xterio Foundation in Switzerland was founded with a Council and a team of technology and entertainment leaders with deep free-to-play games experience, on a mission to develop, publish and distribute high-quality Web2 and Web3 games and interactive entertainment.</p>



<p><strong>About FunPlus</strong></p>



<p>FunPlus is a world-class, independent game developer and publisher headquartered in Switzerland, with offices and operations in China, Japan, Singapore, Spain, Sweden, and the United States. Founded in 2010, FunPlus is an organization that fosters top creative talent with more than 2,000 team members worldwide. Ranked #1 Global Publisher in Strategy Games (2019 and 2020), FunPlus is home to&nbsp;KingsGroup studio&nbsp;who develops hugely popular mobile strategy titles including&nbsp;State of Survival,&nbsp;King of Avalon&nbsp;and&nbsp;Guns of Glory. FunPlus has also positioned itself in the RPG puzzle genre with&nbsp;Call of Antia. In 2021, FunPlus acquired&nbsp;Imagendary Studios&nbsp;working on its first original AAA development. The company is also the founder of FPX（FunPlus Phoenix), one of the world&#8217;s most successful esports organizations, and the 2019 League of Legends World Champions.</p>



<p><strong>About FTX Ventures</strong></p>



<p>FTX Ventures is a multi-stage venture capital fund focused on supporting the world&#8217;s best teams building in crypto and Web3. The fund provides flexible funding and strategic support from FTX and its network of global partners. FTX Ventures currently manages $2B in AUM. </p>



<p><strong>About Makers Fund</strong></p>



<p>Makers Fund is a global interactive entertainment venture capital firm focused on early-stage investments. Makers is dedicated to furthering growth and innovation in the interactive entertainment industry. With more than 90 portfolio companies to date, Makers provides founders strategic value that is deeply catered to companies across the value chain in the industry.</p>



<p><strong>About XPLA</strong></p>



<p>XPLA is the next generation of Web3 mainnet, developed with gamers at the core of its design. Based on the idea of “Explore and Play”, XPLA is the newest innovation in the Web3 gaming space, using COSMOS SDK for optimization. This new infrastructure serves as the bridge between Web2 and Web3 services, and will feature games, art, music and Dapps based on community-driven feedback from users. XPLA places heavy emphasis on User Experience and accessibility to craft the standard in game centric Web3 services, opening up limitless possibilities for blockchain gaming.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Contacts</h2>



<p>fortyseven communications for Xterio<br>xterio@fortyseven.com</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Red Door Digital Launch Reign of Terror Playable Demo Version</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/red-door-digital-launch-reign-of-terror-demo-with-blockchain-game-alliance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=35130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Web3 game studio and publisher will exhibit the playable demo of its first major title, a cyberpunk MMORPG, amid mainstream adoption drive.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="359" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Red-Door-digital.jpeg?resize=640%2C359&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-35131" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Red-Door-digital.jpeg?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Red-Door-digital.jpeg?resize=300%2C168&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Red-Door-digital.jpeg?resize=267%2C150&amp;ssl=1 267w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Web3 game studio and publisher will exhibit the playable demo of its first major title, a cyberpunk MMORPG, amid mainstream adoption drive</strong>.</p>



<p>Red Door Digital, the Web3-ready game studio and publisher, today announced it will unveil the&nbsp;playable demo&nbsp;for its first major game title&nbsp;Reign of Terror&nbsp;at&nbsp;Gamescom 2022&nbsp;in Cologne, Europe&nbsp;’s largest gaming convention. Red Door Digital will exhibit in the B2B section of the event at the&nbsp;Blockchain Game Alliance&nbsp;’s booth, and welcomes all visitors to experience and play the demo in person at&nbsp;Hall 2.1 Stand C038.&nbsp;The event runs from&nbsp;Aug 24 to Aug 28, 2022.</p>



<p>Reign of Terror&nbsp;is a&nbsp;cyberpunk tactical MMORPG&nbsp;set in a Southeast Asia-inspired region. Players can team up into guilds and alliances, siding with either the rebels or the government forces. Characters, weapons, items, and land can be traded as NFTs. The game will be free to play on PC and mobile when it launches later this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Red Door Digital&nbsp;’s team of&nbsp;gaming industry veterans&nbsp;are developing the title in-house, to demonstrate how&nbsp;AAA-quality games&nbsp;can bring&nbsp;mass appeal&nbsp;to Web3.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><em>“Gamescom attracts the best and brightest in the industry, so we&nbsp;’re incredibly excited to launch&nbsp;Reign of Terror&nbsp;’s playable demo here. Red Door Digital is bringing AAA-quality gameplay to Web3, with a&nbsp;Play and Own&nbsp;model that prioritizes entertaining and truly fun games. With our first major title&nbsp;Reign of Terror,&nbsp;we want to deliver on that mission right out the gate,” said&nbsp;Joseph Derflinger, CEO of Red Door Digital.</em></p></blockquote>



<p>Red Door Digital is a Blockchain Game Alliance&nbsp;Gold Member, and this is the first year crypto representatives will exhibit at Gamescom in person. The Web3 game studio raised US$5 million in seed funding earlier in 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">About Red Door Digital</h2>



<p>Founded in 2021, Red Door Digital aims to take the ultra traditional gaming experience to the metaverse. The company is a global-to-local Web 3.0-ready game studio and publisher making award-winning AAA-quality Web3 titles a reality. The team is composed of world-class game designers and developers that not only worked on, but spearheaded the launch of global hits such as FIFA Online, World of Warcraft, EA Origins, and many more.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Report: Blockchain Games, Metaverse Least Hit By Bear Market</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/report-blockchain-games-metaverse-least-hit-by-bear-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 01:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=34863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blockchain games and Metaverse projects seem to be coping with the bear market a lot better than other niches of the market.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="364" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse-1.jpg?resize=640%2C364&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-30818" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse-1.jpg?w=737&amp;ssl=1 737w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/metaverse-1.jpg?resize=300%2C171&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Blockchain games and Metaverse projects seem to be coping with the bear market a lot better than other niches of the market.</strong></p>



<p>The bear market weeds out unnecessary frills and enables legitimate projects to stand out but also cripples portfolios of investors, both big and small. The ongoing market conditions are no different. But one vertical that market participants remain bullish on is – blockchain games and metaverse projects.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Winner in Bear Market</h2>



<p>According to DappRadar’s&nbsp;<a href="https://dappradar.com/blog/how-blockchain-users-reacted-to-the-crypto-contagion-and-the-latest-macro-events" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">report</a>, blockchain games&nbsp;<a href="https://dappradar.com/blog/how-blockchain-users-reacted-to-the-crypto-contagion-and-the-latest-macro-events" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have</a>&nbsp;sidestepped the ensuing bear market and instead ramped up their count by 9.51% in the second quarter of the year. In fact, $2.5 billion were invested in both Q1 and Q2.</p>



<p>June will go down in the history as the worst month for the industry, and even the blockchain gaming space felt the pain registering the lowest per month investment with only $500 million. Weighing on the latest figures, DappRadar’s CEO Skirmantas Januskas commented,</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><em>“We think that blockchain gaming is going to be key in the next two or three years and is going to bring at least 100 million new users into crypto, for one simple reason, they connect NFTs and DeFi. With all three combined, blockchain gaming, NFTs and DeFi you will see something genuinely new and exciting.”</em></p></blockquote>



<p>The report highlighted a decline of 7% in users’ wallet (UAW) activity since Q1. This essentially indicated that users continue to engage with blockchain decentralized applications at roughly the same rate as before the Terra implosion. Simultaneously, the amount of gaming-associated NFT transactions have taken a hit by 51% since Q1. The sales volume has also fallen by 82%.</p>



<p>Besides, the total number of transactions sent to the smart contracts of the gaming sector is way higher than other categories such as DeFi, gambling, exchanges, and marketplaces. Throughout this month as well, transactions in gaming have <a href="https://dappradar.com/industry-overview" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">managed</a> to stay above 24 million per day.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attractive Blockchain for Devs?</h2>



<p>DappRadar revealed that Solana has attracted many NFTs and game developers. This trend can be attributed to low-cost transactions and efficient processing speeds. Despite multiple network outages, blockchain activity has increased by an astonishing 311%.</p>



<p>Owing to the “vibrant gaming community,” WAX has also seen significant traction. Since May, its blockchain activity has grown by 6%.</p>



<p>Demographic-wise, Decentraland holds most popularity in North America, as well as in countries like Austria, Germany, Iceland, Latvia, and Lichtenstein. Axie Infinity, on the other hand, has managed to allure users in Central and South American countries. Meanwhile, Sandbox has garnered popularity in China. The fantasy football game, Sorare has gained a foothold in countries like France, Italy, and Switzerland, as with many football fans across Europe.</p>



<p><a href="https://cryptopotato.com/blockchain-games-least-affected-by-market-turmoil-dappradar-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Axie Infinity CEO: Insider Trading Accusations Are &#8220;Baseless And False&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/axie-infinity-ceo-insider-trading-accusations-are-baseless-and-false/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 02:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=34823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The CEO blamed some media outlets for focusing only on speculations while ignoring the achievements reached by his firm months after the $620m Ronin hack.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie-infinity.jpg?resize=640%2C360&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-26535" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie-infinity.jpg?w=764&amp;ssl=1 764w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie-infinity.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/axie-infinity.jpg?resize=267%2C150&amp;ssl=1 267w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>The CEO blamed some media outlets for focusing only on speculations while ignoring the achievements reached by his firm months after the $620m Ronin hack.</strong></p>



<p>Trung Nguyen – Co-Founder and CEO of Axie Infinity – said the accusations against him of being engaged in insider trading are “baseless and false.” However, he admitted transferring $3 million worth of AXS to “ensure that short-sellers would not be able to front-run the news.”</p>



<p>In March this year, Ronin Bridge – an Ethereum sidechain built for the popular blockchain-based game Axie Infinity – became the victim of one of the largest cryptocurrency hacks ever. Bad actors breached its security and drained over 173,000 ETH. The assets equaled more than $600 million at the time.</p>



<p>The attack quickly grabbed society’s attention, while numerous agencies carried out investigations to find out who stood behind it. The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) estimated that the perpetrator is the notorious North Korean hacking group – the Lazarus Group.</p>



<p>Despite the multi-million theft, Axie Infinity’s team promised to reimburse affected clients. Last month, Ronin Bridge restarted its operations with all user funds returned.</p>



<p>And when all seemed like a bad memory from the crypto’s past, a recent coverage by Bloomberg accused Trung Nguyen – Chief Executive Officer of Axie Infinity – of moving $3 million worth of AXS from the platform to Binance hours before the incident.</p>



<p>The CEO was quick to respond to those charges. In a series of tweets, he said this story “includes speculation of insider trading.” Touching upon the $3 million transfer, he said it indeed occurred, but its goal was to stop AXS short sellers from front-running the news.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">As many of you know, I prefer to operate behind the scenes, but there is a story that dropped today that I want to address with the community, personally.</p>&mdash; Trung Nguyen (@trungfinity) <a href="https://twitter.com/trungfinity/status/1552723314715623425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 28, 2022</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Nguyen further stated that the Founding Team even moved $7.5 million from an Axie multi-sig wallet to Ronin Network to ease the turbulence caused by the hack.</p>



<p>Subsequently, the executive said he is proud of the fact that operations have been restored and all victims received their stolen funds, hinting that this news did not “fit the predetermined narratives” of some media outlets.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><em>“My life’s work is Axie Infinity and the community we’ve created together. I take ownership of the security breach and will use it as a learning experience,” Nguyen concluded.</em></p></blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Binance Recovered Some of the Losses</h2>



<p>A month after the attack, Changpeng Zhao – CEO of Binance – informed that his company retrieved almost $6 million of the $620 million stolen from the Lazarus Group:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><em>“The DPRK hacking group started to move their Axie Infinity stolen funds today. Part of it made to Binance spread across over 86 accounts. $5.8M has been recovered. We have done this many times for other projects in the past, too.”</em></p></blockquote>



<p><a href="https://cryptopotato.com/axie-infinity-ceo-denies-accusation-of-insider-trading/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joyride Games Launch Web3 Game Publishing Platform on Flow￼</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/joyride-games-launch-web3-game-publishing-platform-on-flow%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 01:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Press release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=34660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joyride Games, Inc., a Web3 game publishing platform designed to build, launch and operate blockchain-powered games, today announced the launch of its casual games platform on Flow, the industry-leading blockchain designed to support consumer-scale decentralized applications. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="367" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Joyride-Games.png?resize=640%2C367&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-34661" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Joyride-Games.png?w=750&amp;ssl=1 750w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Joyride-Games.png?resize=300%2C172&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Joyride Games, Inc., a Web3 game publishing platform designed to build, launch and operate blockchain-powered games, today announced the launch of its casual games platform on Flow, the industry-leading blockchain designed to support consumer-scale decentralized applications. </strong></p>



<p>Joyride’s first casual mainstream game that brings the power of games on Web3 to everyone is <em>Solitaire Blitz</em>, racking up >500,000 active users in its first four weeks after launch, becoming a Top 10 blockchain game overall by volume and users and the top game on the Flow blockchain according to DappRadar.</p>



<p>Joyride’s platform for game creators is based on technology that has powered 300 million+ players and top grossing titles on mobile over the past decade. It provides a comprehensive solution to the needs of independent Unity developers as they design, launch, and scale blockchain games with player-owned assets and economies.</p>



<p>“We evaluated blockchain protocols against our needs as a games platform for consumers and found that Flow provides us an excellent solution to on-board users easily and to grow with our ecosystem and player community,” said Omar Siddiqui, CEO and Founder of Joyride. “We are excited to launch&nbsp;<em>Solitaire Blitz</em>&nbsp;on Flow to onboard the next billion users to blockchain.”</p>



<p>“Joyride has built a comprehensive platform to power Web3 games for creative game developers on Unity,” added Mickey Maher, SVP of Partnerships at Dapper Labs. “We share a similar vision to bring the benefits of blockchain to everyone, so we are excited to see them focus on powering the next generation of games and doing so at scale, such as with&nbsp;<em>Solitaire Blitz</em>.”</p>



<p><em>Solitaire Blitz</em>&nbsp;is a polished version of the popular Klondike Solitaire card game, with an updated look, quirky twists and a variety of modes for different types of players. Fans can enjoy relaxing game sessions or compete in tournaments and leagues and earn $RLY tokens. The title has been in beta for the past few months, with thousands of players already spending 40+ minutes/day playing the title in beta.&nbsp;<em>Solitaire Blitz&nbsp;</em>launched on Flow main-net in early June with players able to play directly on blockchain and has quickly grown to 500k+ active users. The app is currently a Top 10 Blockchain Game overall and No. 1 Dapp on Flow.</p>



<p>“We are excited about the early performance of the game, both from an engagement and a technical perspective,” added Omar Siddiqui. “We look forward to growing the title further with our public launch and bringing Web3 gaming to a mass, casual audience that loves playing, relaxing, and competing in classic Solitaire.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3,400 Land Plot Owners Have Tested Yuga Labs&#8217; Otherside Metaverse</title>
		<link>https://fintechs.fi/3400-players-have-tested-yuga-labs-otherside-metaverse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fintechs.fi Staff]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 01:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Metaverse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://fintechs.fi/?p=34631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Otherside, the much-anticipated metaverse gaming platform from the creators of the Bored Ape Yacht Club, is open for business – at least for the owners of a land plot.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="640" height="367" src="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/otherside-yuga-labs.jpg?resize=640%2C367&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-33794" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/otherside-yuga-labs.jpg?w=749&amp;ssl=1 749w, https://i0.wp.com/fintechs.fi/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/otherside-yuga-labs.jpg?resize=300%2C172&amp;ssl=1 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p><strong>Otherside, the much-anticipated metaverse gaming platform from the creators of the Bored Ape Yacht Club, is open for business –&nbsp;at least for the owners of a land plot.</strong></p>



<p>On Saturday, the Yuga Labs-developed game invited 4,300 players—so-called “Voyagers”—for a first-look tech demo and tour of the immersive, ape avatar-navigated online platform. All Otherside players will be required to embark on or view one of these “First Trips” to be able to participate in the game, which has still not yet fully debuted.</p>



<p>All 4,300 players who took part in yesterday’s digital excursion to the “Biogenic Swamp&#8217;” that constitutes the center of Otherside were owners of “Otherdeeds,” deeds to plots of digital land within the platform. In a&nbsp;<a href="https://otherside.xyz/litepaper" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">litepaper</a>&nbsp;released shortly after yesterday’s First Trip, Otherside’s developers announced that only Otherdeed owners and “selected third-party developers” will be permitted to participate in the game during its first phase.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">BR3AKING: <a href="https://twitter.com/OthersideMeta?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">@OthersideMeta</a> holders have tested a trip to the Otherside with 4300+ users. <a href="https://t.co/J9tyNaa2VO" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/J9tyNaa2VO</a></p>&mdash; The Metaverse (@themetav3rse) <a href="https://twitter.com/themetav3rse/status/1548347709899255808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 16, 2022</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>According to the litepaper, “Phase 1” will see Otherdeed owners navigate Voyager’s Journey, an 11-part narrative game “surrounding a mysterious Obelisk that has appeared in the Otherside universe.” In Phase 1, Otherdeed owners will be able to contribute to the platform’s construction and shape its core capabilities as co-developers, via the Otherside Development Kit, the platform’s suite of creation tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We believe in the extraordinary power of community and have seen firsthand how it can be a significant force for good in this industry,” the litepaper stated. “We aim to incentivize, empower, and recognize the expression, creativity, and ingenuity of Otherside’s community of contributors.”</p>



<p>The litepaper also doubled down on Otherside’s commitment to interoperability: the ability for digital assets to freely traverse the many digital neighborhoods, or gaming platforms, that potentially one day could constitute the avatar-navigated metaverse. Proponents of an “open metaverse,” like Yuga Labs, see interoperability as key to the ethos of a democratized and accessible future internet. Such advocates have been vocal about the risk posed by mega corporations like Meta (formerly Facebook),&nbsp;which may attempt to keep their metaverse offerings firmly bordered, in order to retain control over users’ data and analytics.</p>



<p>On Friday, Gordon Goner, one of Yuga Labs’ co-founders, said in a Tweet that Otherside is in direct competition with Web2 “giants,” but expressed optimism that “the future will bend toward the open, interoperable metaverse.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Making something iteratively, with participation from the community along the way and at each milestone, feels like the only authentic way to build a true metaverse.</p>&mdash; GordonGoner.eth (@GordonGoner) <a href="https://twitter.com/GordonGoner/status/1548058794046869510?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 15, 2022</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>The fact that Otherside is currently only accessible to its digital landowners distinguishes it from other leading metaverse platforms, which are open to all internet users. The cheapest Otherdeeds on the market are currently selling for 2.8 ETH, or just shy of $3,800, according to data from&nbsp;<a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/nft/otherdeed-for-otherside" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">CoinGecko</a>. Many are much more expensive. When Otherdeeds launched in April, in a frenzied 24-hour sale&nbsp;that generated $561 million in sales&nbsp;and&nbsp;severely clogged the Ethereum network, that floor price was $5,800.</p>



<p>Exclusivity&nbsp;and&nbsp;extremely high financial barriers to entry&nbsp;are key components of the recipe that has made Yuga’s Bored Ape Yacht Club perhaps the most popular and recognizable NFT brand in the world. Yesterday’s announcement highlights the potential tension between that spirit of scarcity and Yuga’s stated desire to make Otherside central to the fight for an “open metaverse.”</p>



<p>For now, Otherside might be considered the metaverse’s most prominent gated community.</p>



<p><a href="https://decrypt.co/105314/yuga-labs-opens-otherside-for-first-trips-in-bored-ape-metaverse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Source</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
