<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Gamefi &#8211; META KNOW</title>
	<atom:link href="https://metaknow.org/category/gamefi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://metaknow.org</link>
	<description>Your Guide to Becoming the Ultimate Metaverse Expert &#38; Investor</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 18:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://metaknow.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/cropped-K-icon-Meta-Know-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Gamefi &#8211; META KNOW</title>
	<link>https://metaknow.org</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>7 Crypto Games That Let You Earn Real Money in 2023</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/7-crypto-games-that-let-you-earn-real-money-in-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/7-crypto-games-that-let-you-earn-real-money-in-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 18:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crypto games that let you earn real money]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=1789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imagine a world where playing video games isn't just about beating high scores or unlocking achievements. A world where every kill, every win, every in-game item you acquire could turn into real money in your pocket. This isn't a fantasy; it's the fascinating world of play-to-earn (P2E) crypto games. In these games, players can earn cryptocurrency by participating in the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine a world where playing video games isn't just about beating high scores or unlocking achievements. A world where every kill, every win, every in-game item you acquire could turn into real money in your pocket. This isn't a fantasy; it's the fascinating world of play-to-earn (P2E) crypto games.</p>
<p>In these games, players can earn cryptocurrency by participating in the game's ecosystem, which could involve anything from selling in-game items, winning battles, to staking virtual land. These games, usually built on blockchain technology, have disrupted traditional gaming, creating an economy where players can earn from their skills and time.</p>
<p>But how does it work? How can a virtual game generate real money?</p>
<p>Well, it's all about blockchain and Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs). These technologies enable the creation of unique digital assets &#8211; think of them like virtual collector's items, but with a twist. Each of these assets can be bought, sold, or traded for real-world value.</p>
<p>Now that we've laid the groundwork, let's dive into 7 crypto games that let you earn real money in 2023, allowing players to earn while they play.</p>
<h2><strong>1. League of Kingdoms</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://www.leagueofkingdoms.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">League of Kingdoms</a></span> is a full-feature MMO Strategy game on the blockchain where you can own, play, and earn rewards by developing your own kingdoms. It's a decentralised and self-sovereign ecosystem shaped by users. This game is available on Android, iOS, and Windows, and it's classified as easy to play. It's free to play but has some paid tiers for those who want to unlock additional features such as custom avatars, chat rooms, and access to premium items.</p>
<p>In the world of League of Kingdoms, players work together to build and manage a virtual world. Players can construct their kingdom, raise armies, form coalitions, join guilds, battle enemies, and explore the world map. It's possible to purchase land and other NFT assets through the game’s official marketplace or from other players in the OpenSea marketplace.</p>
<p>The game has some unique features such as Drago NFTs, dragon-like creatures that are formidable allies of the kingdom and decisive combatants. The in-game currency, $LOKA, is used to power the game, and players can earn LOKA tokens while playing the game’s quests. These tokens can then be used to purchase various virtual goods like cosmetic items, weapons, armor, pets, mounts, and buildings.</p>
<p>Moreover, the game also features a play-to-earn mechanism powered by the Dragon Soul Token ($DST), a utility token. The ownership of NFTs allows players to earn cryptocurrencies, with most gaming costs allocated towards rewarding active players and landlords.</p>
<h2><strong>2. Realm</strong></h2>
<p>Built on the Ethereum and Polygon blockchains, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://www.realm.art/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Realm</a></span> is a play-to-earn metaverse game where players can create and explore user-generated worlds. The game is immersive and offers a unique virtual reality experience, setting it apart from other crypto games. Players can explore realms to discover rare NFTs, earn $REALM tokens, trade with each other, and socialize with others, making it more interactive and engaging.</p>
<p>With Realm, players aren't just playing a game, they're part of an interactive, digital community. Whether you're building a world, exploring new environments, or meeting new friends, Realm offers a unique, immersive gaming experience that's definitely worth a try.</p>
<h2><strong>3. Splinterlands</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://splinterlands.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Splinterlands</a></span> is a digital, collectible card game where players build up their collection of cards, each of which is a unique NFT, and battle against others. The game uses blockchain technology to ensure fair play and secure ownership of the digital assets, offering players a new level of gameplay and card ownership. The game is available on both web and mobile platforms, making it accessible to a wide range of players.</p>
<p>In Splinterlands, players collect, trade, upgrade, and battle with their cards to earn ranking points and climb up the leaderboard. The game also features a real-money economy where players can earn and spend the game's native currency, Dark Energy Crystals (DEC). These can be earned through winning battles and completing quests, and spent on new cards or entering into tournaments.</p>
<p>Splinterlands uses NFTs (non-fungible tokens) to represent each card in the game, ensuring that each one is unique and owned by a specific player. Players can trade their NFTs with others or sell them on the game’s official marketplaces, potentially earning significant profits if they have rare or powerful cards.</p>
<p>Earning potential for Splinterlands players is tied to their strategic ability, gameplay performance, and the time they invest in the game. As players win battles and complete quests, they earn DEC which can then be traded for real-world currencies. The more skilled and active a player is, the more they can potentially earn.</p>
<h2><strong>4. Tamadoge (TAMA)</strong></h2>
<p>Step aside Mario, there's a new game in town: <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://tamadoge.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tamadoge</a></span>. Tamadoge is a meme project turned thrilling play-to-earn (P2E) gaming platform that is quickly gaining traction in the crypto gaming world. Its arcade collection kicked off with &#8220;Super Doge,&#8221; a game that takes players on a coin-collecting, SECKnights-battling adventure reminiscent of our beloved plumber. With a leaderboard offering bountiful rewards in TAMA tokens, the game taps into the competitive spirit of players and makes every jump count.</p>
<p>But Tamadoge is no one-trick pony with plans to develop five arcade games. The platform offers a free-to-play version, making it accessible for players to test the waters before diving into the full P2E game. For that, players need a Doge NFT available on OpenSea, ranging from common to ultra-rare tiers. Each game sets you back just one TAMA token, a small price for the thrill of the game.</p>
<h2><strong>5. Meta Apes</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://metaapesgame.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Meta Apes</a></span> is a captivating play-to-earn Web3 game that takes you to a post-apocalyptic era where humans are history, and apes reign supreme. As a player, you control a unique Meta-Ape, each possessing distinctive traits and abilities. Your mission, if you choose to accept it, is not just survival, but the dominance of space. Cooperation is key &#8211; you and your ape clan must collaborate to conquer and win the interstellar race.</p>
<p>Meta Apes cleverly employs a dual token model to enhance gameplay and create an intriguing economic dynamic. SHELL serves as the in-game currency, allowing you to purchase essential resources. However, to truly evolve your ape and establish dominance, you'll need PEEL, the governance token. PEEL can be staked and strategically used to upgrade your Meta-Ape, providing a layer of complexity and strategy to the game.</p>
<p>Free to play yet rich in strategy, Meta Apes immerses players in a world where apes lead the space race. It's a wild ride that combines post-apocalyptic survival, interspecies governance, and a race to space, creating a unique and engaging play-to-earn gaming experience. With every SHELL spent and PEEL staked, players are drawn deeper into this intriguing, ape-dominated world.</p>
<h2><strong>6. Crazy Defense Heroes</strong></h2>
<p>Brace yourself for an adrenaline rush with <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://crazydefenseheroes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Crazy Defense Heroes</a></span>, a captivating blend of tower defense and card collection that's sure to hook any strategy game enthusiast. Here, your kingdom is under threat from relentless monster hordes, and it's up to you to fend them off using defensive structures and special abilities. With every battle fought, you collect cards that allow you to fine-tune your defense strategy, making each fight a thrilling blend of action and strategic planning.</p>
<p>What sets Crazy Defense Heroes apart in the realm of crypto games is the integration of its native utility token, TOWER. This Ethereum-based token is not just a means of acquiring NFTs within the Crazy Kings franchise. It's also your ticket to exclusive events and tournaments, adding an additional layer of excitement to the gameplay.</p>
<p>Beyond its play-to-earn mechanics, TOWER also plays a crucial role in the governance of the game. As a governance token, it gives players a say in the evolution of the game, reinforcing the sense of community and player engagement. Crazy Defense Heroes successfully blends thrilling gameplay with strategic depth and community engagement, making it a compelling entry in the world of crypto gaming.</p>
<h2><strong>7. Galaxy Fight Club</strong></h2>
<p>Get ready for an interstellar showdown with <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://galaxyfightclub.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Galaxy Fight Club (GFC)</a></span>, a thrilling cross-platform PvP MOBA (Multiplayer Online Battle Arena) where your NFT avatars are the stars of the show. Here, your Bored Ape Yacht Club (BAYC) Apes can go head-to-head with a friend's Cryptopunks in an epic cosmic battle. Played in fast-paced 3v3 battles that last roughly five minutes, the game is an exhilarating mix of strategy and chaos. The goal is simple yet challenging: be the first team to score 20 kills.</p>
<p>But Galaxy Fight Club is more than just a celestial battleground. It's also a space where your NFT avatars can grow and evolve. The game employs the GCOIN utility token for a range of in-game transactions. Whether you're opening loot boxes won in battle, forging new weapons, or training your fighters to become more formidable, GCOIN is your key to enhancing your gameplay experience.</p>
<p>Unique to Galaxy Fight Club is that GCOIN tokens are only minted by Genesis Galaxy Fighters. This not only makes them a prized in-game asset but also contributes to their value on secondary markets. Galaxy Fight Club merges the excitement of MOBA gaming with the tangible rewards of play-to-earn mechanisms, all set within a vibrant universe populated by your favorite NFT avatars.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/7-crypto-games-that-let-you-earn-real-money-in-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Game Changers: Top 10 GameFi Blogs in 2023</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/the-game-changers-top-10-gamefi-blogs-in-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/the-game-changers-top-10-gamefi-blogs-in-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 17:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Best GameFi Blogs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=1787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent years, GameFi (Game Finance) has emerged as an influential innovation in the ever-evolving realm of blockchain technology, captivating the attention of gamers and crypto enthusiasts alike. Combining the thrill of gaming with the potential for substantial financial gains, GameFi has rapidly taken the world by storm, redefining the landscape of interactive entertainment. However, as the GameFi revolution surges...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, GameFi (Game Finance) has emerged as an influential innovation in the ever-evolving realm of blockchain technology, captivating the attention of gamers and crypto enthusiasts alike.</p>
<p>Combining the thrill of gaming with the potential for substantial financial gains, GameFi has rapidly taken the world by storm, redefining the landscape of interactive entertainment.</p>
<p>However, as the GameFi revolution surges forward, it becomes crucial for gamers and other enthusiasts to stay ahead of the curve, remaining informed and empowered. With countless projects, platforms, and trends flooding the digital realm, a reliable compass is needed to navigate this exciting new frontier so that enthusiasts can get to know the <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://blog.feedspot.com/gamefi_blogs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">best GameFi blogs</a></span> to learn about play-to-earn gaming projects.</p>
<p>In this article, we've curated a list of the most informative and thought-provoking GameFi blogs that are leading the charge in this rapidly evolving ecosystem.</p>
<p>These blogs serve as the go-to platforms for expert analysis, deep dives into emerging GameFi projects, comprehensive reviews of gaming tokens, and tutorials to help you unlock the full potential of this disruptive convergence. Whether you're a seasoned crypto investor, a dedicated gamer exploring new possibilities, or a curious newcomer intrigued by the concept of GameFi, these blogs provide a wealth of valuable information, fostering a deep understanding of GameFi concepts.</p>
<h2>Without further delay, here are the Top 10 GameFi blogs to learn about play-to-earn gaming in 2023.</h2>
<h2><strong>1. GameFi.org</strong></h2>
<p>When it comes to exploring the internet for information on GameFi, one blog stands head and shoulders above the rest: <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://gamefi.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GameFi.org</a></span>.</p>
<p>GameFi.org sets the gold standard for comprehensive coverage, expert insights, and unrivaled expertise in the world of GameFi. The play-to-earn blog has emerged as the go-to destination for enthusiasts seeking the latest updates, in-depth analysis, and invaluable resources in the GameFi universe.</p>
<p>The blog consistently delivers cutting-edge content that covers a broad range of topics, from play-to-earn mechanics and innovative GameFi projects to market trends and investment strategies. This exceptional blog truly sets the benchmark for excellence in the GameFi space.</p>
<p>GameFi.org claims to be an all-encompassing hub for game finance with features that include: GameFi Hub, Launchpad, Marketplace, Guild Hub, and Metaverse. From its comprehensive guides to its thought-provoking articles, GameFi.org caters to both seasoned investors and avid gamers looking to tap into the lucrative potential of GameFi.</p>
<h2><strong>2. Polemos.io</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://polemos.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Polemos</a></span> prides itself on being an information and education provider, game asset lending and staking service, and community for gamers that believes in the massive potential of play-to-earn blockchain games, with a mission to help ease the onboarding process of new players and users into the GameFi world.</p>
<p>One of the GameFi blog's amazing features is the Polemos Scholarship Programs, which are open to anyone interested in Play and Earn games and provide an opportunity for members of the blockchain gaming community to enjoy some of the top blockchain games without spending money upfront to acquire digital assets.</p>
<h2><strong>3. Metaknow.org</strong></h2>
<p>Metaknow.org is a platform that prides itself on being the go-to blog for information on play-to-earn games, NFT gaming projects, the metaverse, NFTs, and crypto games.</p>
<p>The team at Metaknow is passionate about enlightening gamers on how they can make money from playing games they'd normally play for free and protecting gamers from being exploited by gaming projects that only want to exploit the gaming industry without giving anything back to gamers.</p>
<p>To achieve this, this group of experts churns out articles, blog posts, and guides based on in-depth research that provides gamers with information about the best play-to-earn games currently available on which they can maximize their gaming skills.</p>
<h2><strong>4. Play-To-Earn Diary</strong></h2>
<p>Reaching over 1 million users on social media platforms each month, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://playtoearndiary.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Play-to-Earn Diary</a></span> is a GameFi blog on a mission to have a website and social media channels where play-to-earn enthusiasts can discover awesome content at their fingertips, helping them make the most of their P2E gaming experiences.</p>
<p>From popular P2E games like Axie Infinity, Upland, and The Sandbox to upcoming gaming projects, the play to earn diary helps gamers access information that can help them make investment decisions when it comes to their time, energy, and skills.</p>
<h2><strong>5. NFTandGameFi.com</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NFTandGameFi</a></span> is an amazing blog where GameFi enthusiasts can access information on play-to-earn games, DeFi, the metaverse, and the latest news and updates on popular GameFi projects in the industry.</p>
<p>If you're planning to dive into the decentralized world of GameFi, NFTandGameFi is an ideal place to start gathering information on the GameFi world.</p>
<h2><strong>6. DappRadar</strong></h2>
<p>Though not primarily a GameFi blog, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://dappradar.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DappRadar</a></span> appears on this list because the blog is an ideal place to learn about GameFi and access information about the best projects on specific blockchains.</p>
<p>In addition, the website also makes it easy to track information on GameFi dApps.</p>
<h2><strong>7. BiteBi.com</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://bitebi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BiteBi</a></span> is a digital publication covering the intersection between technology and money with a focus on providing information on play-to-earn games, NFT gaming projects, blockchain, DeFi, the metaverse, and cryptocurrency projects.</p>
<p>If you want an all-in-one site for all things technology and finance, then you should definitely consider BiteBi.</p>
<h2><strong>8. Joystick's GameFi Blog</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://joystick.club/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Joystick Club</a></span> is primarily a pay-to-play games arcade that is powered by Bitcoin Cash. On Joystick's GameFi blog, you can read the latest news on blockchain games and play-to-earn projects.</p>
<p>However, you'll have to subscribe to get full access to blog posts on the site.</p>
<h2><strong>9. Bitcoininsider.org</strong></h2>
<p>Don't let the name deceive you; <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://www.bitcoininsider.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bitcoin Insider</a></span> is a platform that constantly provides its readers with information on GameFi projects, play-to-earn games, and crypto gambling games. In addition, you can access information about the crypto market, blockchains, DeFi, and Web3 on Bitcoin Insider.</p>
<h2><strong>10. News.coincu.com</strong></h2>
<p><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://news.coincu.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Coincu</a></span> is a crypto news and update blog that reviews GameFi projects and provides information on upcoming GameFi projects that gamers and crypto enthusiasts can invest in.</p>
<p>On Coincu, you can find information on the best gaming dApps available on blockchains, NFT games, and news about major DeFi and cryptocurrency platforms like Binance, Coinbase, and Ethereum.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/the-game-changers-top-10-gamefi-blogs-in-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Axie Infinity Dead?</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/is-axie-infinity-dead/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/is-axie-infinity-dead/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 17:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Is Axie Infinity Dead?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=1784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As one of the pioneering play-to-earn blockchain games, Axie Infinity captured the attention of gamers and investors alike, emerging as a game-changer in the gaming industry. During the COVID-19 pandemic, the game provided a source of income for many Filipinos, skyrocketing its popularity. However, recent challenges and a decline in market value have raised questions about the future of Axie...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As one of the pioneering play-to-earn blockchain games, Axie Infinity captured the attention of gamers and investors alike, emerging as a game-changer in the gaming industry. During the COVID-19 pandemic, the game provided a source of income for many Filipinos, skyrocketing its popularity.</p>
<p>However, recent challenges and a decline in market value have raised questions about the future of Axie Infinity. In this article, we will explore the rise of Axie Infinity, analyze the challenges it currently faces, and assess its potential for recovery and future growth.</p>
<h2><strong>Everything You Need to Know About Axie Infinity</strong></h2>
<p>Axie Infinity, developed by the Vietnamese-based gaming company Sky Mavis, revolutionized the gaming landscape by introducing play-to-earn mechanics. The game centers around collecting, breeding, battling, and building kingdoms with virtual pets known as Axies. These adorable creatures became digital assets that players could own and trade, attracting a passionate community of players.</p>
<p>The play-to-earn mechanics of Axie Infinity offered players a unique opportunity to generate income while enjoying the game. By participating in battles and completing in-game tasks, players earned Smooth Love Potion (SLP), an in-game token that could be exchanged for real-world value.</p>
<p>This concept proved especially appealing to individuals looking for alternative income streams, and the game gained significant traction, particularly in the Philippines.</p>
<p>The Axie Scholarship program emerged as a popular way for players with limited resources or time to participate in the game. Through this program, experienced players, known as managers, would lend their Axies to others, known as scholars, who would play the game on their behalf. The rewards earned would then be shared between the manager and the scholars, providing a mutually beneficial arrangement.</p>
<h2><strong>Is Axie Infinity Declining?</strong></h2>
<p>Despite its initial success, Axie Infinity has faced several challenges, leading to a decline in market performance. Like many altcoins, the game experienced a significant drop in market capitalization, losing over 90% of its value from its peak. This decline can be attributed to the broader market trends affecting cryptocurrencies with investors now turning their attention to artificial intelligence, metaverse, web3 and meme projects.</p>
<p>Furthermore, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/03/29/tech/axie-infinity-ronin-hack/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Axie Infinity suffered a major setback in March 23, 2022 when it became the target of a high-profile hack</a></span>. Approximately $615 million in cryptocurrency was stolen, primarily from the <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a style="color: #0000ff;" href="https://roninchain.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ronin network</a></span>, the blockchain infrastructure supporting Axie Infinity. The theft, orchestrated by exploiting stolen private keys, resulted in a loss of user confidence and cast a shadow over the game's reputation.</p>
<p>The immediate aftermath of the hack has seen a significant decrease in the number of daily active users, as players became concerned about the security of their assets, with the numbers currently at around 25000 users from a peak of 2.78 million users during the COVID-19 pandemic. Axie Infinity's reputation took a hit, and rebuilding trust has become a top priority for the developers.</p>
<h2><strong>Will Axie Infinity Recover?</strong></h2>
<p>While the path to recovery may be challenging, and Axie Infinity may not return to its pre-pandemic value, the play-to-earn gaming project still possesses potential for revitalization. The game remains an influential player within the play-to-earn gaming sphere, leveraging its passionate community and innovative gameplay mechanics.</p>
<p>To regain trust and rebuild its user base, Axie Infinity and its developers must prioritize bolstering security measures and enhancing transparency. Implementing stringent security protocols, conducting frequent audits, and fostering open communication with the community are crucial steps to prevent future hacks and restore player confidence.</p>
<p>Moreover, the Axie Infinity team should focus on improving the overall gameplay experience and expanding the features that initially attracted users. Continuous innovation, such as introducing new Axie breeds, refining breeding and battling mechanics, and forging partnerships with other prominent blockchain games, can reignite interest and entice players to return.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Axie Infinity's recovery is intricately tied to the wider adoption of blockchain technology and the acceptance of cryptocurrencies. As the blockchain and crypto industry matures, more individuals and investors will become acquainted with the concept of play-to-earn games, potentially leading to a resurgence of interest in Axie Infinity and similar projects.</p>
<h3><strong>Conclusion</strong></h3>
<p>Axie Infinity's journey from its remarkable rise during the pandemic to its current challenges demonstrates the dynamic nature of the blockchain gaming industry. While the game faces significant hurdles, it still harbours the potential to adapt, recover, and thrive. By addressing security concerns, enhancing gameplay, and capitalizing on the growing acceptance of cryptocurrencies, Axie Infinity can navigate the evolving landscape and bounce back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/is-axie-infinity-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Discover the Cutest Roblox Avatars of 2023 &#8211; Our Top Picks!</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/discover-the-cutest-roblox-avatars-of-2023/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/discover-the-cutest-roblox-avatars-of-2023/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Moeen Akram]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 03:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=1598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you looking to create the cutest Roblox avatars possible? Roblox is a popular online gaming platform that lets players create their own avatars and play games with friends. Creating an adorable avatar is a great way to show off your personality and stand out from the crowd. Introduction Roblox is a popular online gaming platform that offers a wide...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you looking to create the cutest Roblox avatars possible? Roblox is a popular online gaming platform that lets players create their own avatars and play games with friends. Creating an adorable avatar is a great way to show off your personality and stand out from the crowd.</p>





<h2 class="kt-adv-heading_1099de-d8 wp-block-kadence-advancedheading" data-kb-block="kb-adv-heading_1099de-d8">Introduction</h2>



<p>Roblox is a popular online gaming platform that offers a wide variety of <a href="https://metaknow.org/metaverse-gaming-5-best-play-to-earn-games/">games to play</a>. With over 100 million active users, <a href="https://metaknow.org/a-complete-guide-to-creating-your-metaverse-avatar-for-free1580-2/">creating a unique avatar</a> that stands out from the crowd can be a daunting task. However, with a little bit of creativity and imagination, anyone can create a cute and adorable avatar that reflects their personality and style.</p>



<h2 class="kt-adv-heading_f034e2-0a wp-block-kadence-advancedheading" data-kb-block="kb-adv-heading_f034e2-0a">Understanding Roblox Avatars</h2>



<p>it's important to understand the basic components of a Roblox avatar. Roblox avatars are made up of several components, including a head, torso, arms, and legs. These components can be customized with various accessories, clothing, animations, and colors.</p>



<h2 class="kt-adv-heading_a8fb5f-3f wp-block-kadence-advancedheading" data-kb-block="kb-adv-heading_a8fb5f-3f">Cutest Roblox Avatars: Our Top Picks</h2>



<p>Let's start with the main attraction of this article, the cutest Roblox avatars. Here are our top picks for the most adorable avatars that you can use in Roblox:</p>



<ol>
<li>Baby Shark Avatar: If you love the famous children's song &#8220;Baby Shark,&#8221; you will love this avatar. The Baby Shark avatar is a cute blue shark with a yellow belly and a friendly smile.</li>



<li>Kawaii Cat Avatar: This avatar is perfect for cat lovers. The Kawaii Cat avatar is a cute white cat with a pink nose and adorable blue eyes. It comes with a pink bow on its head and a matching pink collar.</li>



<li>Panda Avatar: Who can resist a cute panda? The Panda avatar is a black and white panda with a friendly smile. It comes with a bamboo stick that it carries around.</li>



<li>Bunny Avatar: The Bunny avatar is perfect for Easter or anyone who loves cute bunnies. This avatar is a white bunny with a pink nose and cute floppy ears.</li>



<li>Unicorn Avatar: If you love unicorns, you will love the Unicorn avatar. This avatar is a cute pink unicorn with a rainbow mane and tail. It also has a golden horn and cute little wings.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Other Cute Roblox Avatars</h2>



<p>Aside from our top picks, there are still many other cute Roblox avatars that you can use. Here are some of them:</p>



<ul>
<li>Pusheen Avatar: Pusheen is a famous cartoon character that has become a popular avatar in Roblox. The Pusheen avatar is a cute gray cat with a friendly smile.</li>



<li>Pikachu Avatar: Who doesn't know Pikachu? The Pikachu avatar is perfect for Pokemon fans. It is a yellow mouse with red cheeks and pointy ears.</li>



<li>Hello Kitty Avatar: Hello Kitty is a famous Japanese cartoon character that has also become a popular avatar in Roblox. The Hello Kitty avatar is a cute white cat with a red bow on its head.</li>



<li>Corgi Avatar: Corgis are known for their cute stubby legs and friendly demeanor. The Corgi avatar is a cute brown and white corgi with a happy expression.</li>



<li>Teddy Bear Avatar: The Teddy Bear avatar is perfect for anyone who loves stuffed animals. This avatar is a cute brown teddy bear with a friendly smile.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="kt-adv-heading_649391-56 wp-block-kadence-advancedheading" data-kb-block="kb-adv-heading_649391-56">How to Get Inspiration for Your Avatar</h2>



<p>If you're struggling to come up with ideas for your cute avatar, here are a few sources of inspiration to consider:</p>



<ul>
<li>Look for inspiration from popular culture, such as movies, TV shows, or video games.</li>



<li>Check out other players' avatars for inspiration.</li>



<li>Browse through the Roblox catalog to see the latest accessories and clothing items.</li>



<li>Experiment with different styles and themes to find what works best for you.</li>
</ul>



<p>Also Read: <a href="https://metaknow.org/forest-knight-play-to-earn-game-review841-2/">Forest Knight Play-to-Earn Game Review</a></p>



<h2 class="kt-adv-heading_a331fc-46 wp-block-kadence-advancedheading" data-kb-block="kb-adv-heading_a331fc-46">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, the cutest Roblox avatars can bring a touch of cuteness and fun to your gaming experience. Whether you love animals, cartoon characters, or stuffed toys, there is an avatar out there for you. Don't be afraid to customize your avatar and make it even cuter. After all, Roblox is all about having fun and expressing yourself. So, go ahead and choose your favorite cute avatar and start playing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/discover-the-cutest-roblox-avatars-of-2023/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zed Run NFT Horse Racing Game Review</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/zed-run-nft-horse-racing-game-review859-2/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/zed-run-nft-horse-racing-game-review859-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 22:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zed Run]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Horse racing is one of the oldest games in history, and as such, it's important to explore new ways to modernize the game and improve it to meet the standards of the 21st century gaming industry. This quest to improve horse racing and the gaming space in general has seen the integration of technological concepts such as virtual reality (VR)...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Horse racing is one of the oldest games in history, and as such, it's important to explore new ways to modernize the game and improve it to meet the standards of the 21st century gaming industry.</p>
<p>This quest to improve horse racing and the gaming space in general has seen the integration of technological concepts such as virtual reality (VR) to make gaming more interesting and attractive.</p>
<p>In the midst of the scramble to adapt the horse racing space to emerging technological innovations, Zed Run has taken the bull by the horns by introducing a new way to make players enjoy their horse racing gaming experience.</p>
<p>So without further ado, let's find out the things that differentiate Zed Run from other horse racing games currently available online.</p>
<h2><strong>What is Zed Run?</strong></h2>
<p>Zed Run is a horse racing game that prides itself on being the meeting point between horse racing and blockchain technology.</p>
<p>Zed Run integrates horse racing with blockchain technology, the metaverse, and NFTs in an open market.</p>
<p>Zed Run launched in January 2019 as the first Non-Fungible Token (NFT) project that enabled users to buy, breed, and race their very own digital racehorses, which are represented in the form of NFTs.</p>
<h2><strong>How Does it Work?</strong></h2>
<p>Launched in 2018 in Australia by Virtually Human Studio, with over one million completed races, Zed Run allows players to buy, breed, and race digital NFT horses. There are currently over two hundred thousand horses in the game, and the horses (NFT characters) are split up into four bloodlines: Nakamoto (the rarest), Szabo, Finney, and Buterin (the most common).</p>
<p>Contrary to the traditional chance-focused horse racing games, Zed Run is a skill and strategy game, with the likelihood of a horse winning a race being determined by characteristics such as bloodline, genotype, and breed type.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Get Started in Zed Run</strong></h2>
<p>To get started, you begin the game by creating an account (a &#8220;stable&#8221;) through the <a href="https://zed.run/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">official Zed Run website</a>.</p>
<p>Once you're done setting up your account, you can go ahead and purchase a starting racehorse through the official Zed Run OpenSea collection.</p>
<p>Once you've completed the purchase of your first horse, you can participate in the &#8220;discovery races&#8221; to get you ready to compete in races for prize money.</p>
<p>To compete in races with a prize pool, you must pay a buy-in fee, and the higher the buy-in, the higher the prize pool.</p>
<p>In most of these races, 12 horses that belong to a similar class compete against each other, and the first six horses to cross the finish line earn a share of the prize money.</p>
<p>The higher you finish among the six horses, the higher the percentage of the prize pool you earn.</p>
<h2><strong>How To Earn Money In Zed Run</strong></h2>
<p>To earn money in Zed Run, you need to first purchase a racehorse. Racehorses are available on the <a href="https://opensea.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OpenSea NFT marketplace</a> for as little as $10, so buying one shouldn't be a financial burden.</p>
<p>Once you've completed the purchase of your racehorse, you can earn crypto by winning races or breeding and selling prized horses.</p>
<p>To increase your chances of winning a race, you can either get a better horse, either by buying or breeding one, or simply participate in races in a lower class where your horse stands a chance of winning.</p>
<p>You can withdraw your crypto earnings at any point or convert them to fiat money as you withdraw.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/zed-run-nft-horse-racing-game-review859-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Six Dragons Review</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/the-six-dragons-review850-2/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/the-six-dragons-review850-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 23:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Six Dragons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The arrival of play-to-earn (P2E) games in the gaming industry has led to the creation of games with various amazing features that make them different from traditional games. These play-to-earn games have brought many exciting features that will change the way the operational and financial models in the gaming industry work. We've seen the use of blockchain technology, passive income,...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The arrival of play-to-earn (P2E) games in the gaming industry has led to the creation of games with various amazing features that make them different from traditional games.</p>
<p>These play-to-earn games have brought many exciting features that will change the way the operational and financial models in the gaming industry work.</p>
<p>We've seen the use of blockchain technology, passive income, player ownership of in-game assets, free-to-play, and player control among many other exciting features that we've witnessed since the arrival of play-to-earn games on the gaming scene.</p>
<p>Set in a fantasy world, The Six Dragons is at the forefront of the new P2E genre of gaming. This open-world RPG game has some amazing features incorporated into it that offer an exciting experience to players.</p>
<p>So what is The six dragons? What are the exciting features that make it different from other games?</p>
<p>These and many more questions will be answered in this article.</p>
<h2><strong>What is The Six Dragons (TSD)? </strong></h2>
<p>The Six of Dragons (TSD) is an open-world RPG adventure game inspired by iconic games such as Skyrim.</p>
<p>The game is a free-to-play single-player fantasy RPG that is based on the blockchain and uses features such as blockchain technology, passive income, player ownership of NFT in-game assets, and governance (player control) to create an adventurous game that provides an exciting user experience to gamers.</p>
<h2><strong>How Does it Work?</strong></h2>
<p>Set in the fantasy world of Nemberus, TSD is an adventure game with a 256 km2 map of open land and 1 billion dungeons that players can explore.</p>
<p>The game features three character types, which are warriors, wizards, and clerics, and you come across these characters in different monster-like forms as your adventure takes you through the forests, mountains, lakes, and rivers, scattered with villages, dungeons, arenas, and castles.</p>
<p>In the fight against these characters, you need swords for warriors, staffs for wizards, and maces for clerics, with 26 variants of each weapon.</p>
<p>Meanwhile: <a href="https://r.atlasearth.com/ykDj6L08eub" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Atlas Earth is offering passive income opportunities that gamers can't resist.</a></p>
<p>As a player, you start the game at level 1 (Lv1) and reach higher levels when you earn XP points through various in-game interactions, such as collecting materials or killing monsters.</p>
<p>As you reach higher levels, the skills of your hero, the monsters you will encounter, the level of portals and dungeons you will find, and the in-game items such as weapons and armor that you have all change and improve.</p>
<p>You can hunt for loot, farm for resources, upgrade their skills, and craft new items like weapons and armor via the Blockchain Blacksmith Service feature in TSD.</p>
<p>The Blockchain Blacksmith Service feature allows players to craft new tokenized in-game items by paying other members of the community who act as blacksmiths.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Start Playing The Six Dragons</strong></h2>
<p>As someone who's new to the Six Dragons game, there are a couple of steps you need to take to start playing the game; here's a step-by-step guide on how to get started.</p>
<h3>1. Install  <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.enjin.mobile.wallet&hl=en&gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Enjin Wallet</strong></a></h3>
<p>TSD is an Ethereum blockchain-based game, so you need a blockchain wallet to start playing the game.</p>
<p>Enjin Wallet is the only wallet currently supported for playing the game in blockchain mode.</p>
<p>The wallet allows you to use your crypto and NFT assets in-game as well as receive the items you earn from the game straight to your wallet.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Register your account</strong></h3>
<p>Once you've installed and connected your wallet with the game, the next step is to register your account in the game.</p>
<p>On the main menu, select the &#8220;Blockchain Login&#8221; option and choose &#8220;Register new user,&#8221; then fill in your personal information, such as your email address, username, and password. Press &#8220;Register&#8221; once you've filled in the information and wait for an email that confirms your registration.</p>
<h3><strong>3. Start Playing the Game</strong></h3>
<p>Once you've received the confirmation email, go ahead and start playing the game.</p>
<h2><strong>Amazing Features of the Six Dragons</strong></h2>
<p>From an adventurous theme that takes you through forests, mountains, lakes, rivers, villages, dungeons, arenas, and castles to the NFT assets that the game allows you to craft and sell to other players on the marketplace, here are some features of the six dragons.</p>
<h3><strong>1. Player ownership and control</strong></h3>
<p>Player ownership and control of in-game assets is the backbone of TSD; the project uses tokenized ownership governance that gives control to players and allows them to vote on decisions that affect the game and community at large.</p>
<p>As a player, you can create weapons, items, and equipment on the Ethereum blockchain and freely sell or trade them with other players on the NFT marketplace, thus creating a player-driven, decentralized financial economy.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Blockchain-based Gaming</strong></h3>
<p>Every aspect of the Six Dragons game is on the blockchain; you can play the game on the blockchain and also send and receive your in-game assets through the NFT marketplace on the Ethereum blockchain.</p>
<h3><strong>3. Passive Income</strong></h3>
<p>Holders of the Six Dragons governance NFT earn passive income through a revenue share over all in-game transactions from trading and item creation.</p>
<p><strong>Should You Invest in the Six Dragons?</strong></p>
<p>The first thing you need to understand is that the game is free-to-play, although you can buy in-game assets to upgrade your weapons and increase your earning potential.</p>
<p>However, whether you choose to invest your money is at your own discretion, and it's more advisable to consider doing so after you've played the game to some extent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/the-six-dragons-review850-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nine Chronicles: Play-to-Earn On A Decentralized Platform</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/nine-chronicles-play-to-earn-on-a-decentralized-platform846-2/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/nine-chronicles-play-to-earn-on-a-decentralized-platform846-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 12:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nine Chronicles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=846</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nine Chronicles joins a long list of play-to-earn (P2E) games that have launched in recent years. These play-to-earn games aim to change the way the financial system works in the gaming space through the power of blockchain technology. And using cryptocurrencies and NFTs, they have made it possible for gamers to earn rewards for investing both time and money in...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nine Chronicles joins a long list of play-to-earn (P2E) games that have launched in recent years.</p>
<p>These play-to-earn games aim to change the way the financial system works in the gaming space through the power of blockchain technology.</p>
<p>And using cryptocurrencies and NFTs, they have made it possible for gamers to earn rewards for investing both time and money in games.</p>
<p>However, despite the potential in the blockchain gaming industry, there have been hits and misses, with many P2E games failing to deliver on their promises to gamers.</p>
<p>So with all these happenings in the blockchain gaming space, is Nine Chronicles a hit or a miss? And should you invest your time and money in this game?</p>
<p>Let's find out these answers and more in this article.</p>
<h2><strong>What is Nine Chronicles?</strong></h2>
<p>Nine Chronicles is a free-to-play MMORPG game that combines gameplay, mining, and governance using the blockchain to allow players to trade the digital assets they earn in game while also converting their computing power into $NCG tokens (Nine Chronicles Gold).</p>
<p>The game features players exploring the nine realms and competing with other players in the dungeons so they can get raw materials to craft unique items they can use to improve the way they play the game.</p>
<p>The unique items they find can be used to enhance their skills or traded for cryptocurrency or NFTs with other players.</p>
<h2><strong>How Does Nine Chronicles Work?</strong></h2>
<p>Unlike in traditional games, in which a gaming company operates the game and decides the gameplay, fees, eligibility criteria, and other aspects of the game, Nine Chronicles uses a different mode of operation.</p>
<p>Just like Bitcoin, the Nine Chronicles platform is a decentralized open-source ecosystem in which gamers and miners connect to each other to power a distributed game network.</p>
<p>In addition, the game is governed by its players, with miners and gamers playing a part in the decision-making process for running the game and the community at large.</p>
<p>In return for their in-game activities and mining operations, gamers and miners are rewarded with NFTs and $NCG (the governance currency of the Nine Chronicles platform).</p>
<h3><strong>How to Start Playing Nine Chronicles</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li>To get started, go to <a href="http://nine-chronicles.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://nine-chronicles.com</a>.</li>
<li>Click the &#8220;Play Now&#8221; button on the homepage.</li>
<li>After that, you'll be asked to sign in with your Twitter account so you can get your invitation code.</li>
<li>The installer is downloaded automatically, after which you will click the &#8220;Create Account&#8221; button and enter information such as your password and username.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Amazing Features of Nine Chronicles</strong></h2>
<p>Nine Chronicles has some amazing features that make it different from just a mere addition to the play-to-earn games currently live on blockchains.</p>
<p>Here are some amazing features of The Nine Chronicles.</p>
<h3><strong>1. Open-source decentralized ecosystem</strong></h3>
<p>The standout feature of the gaming platform is its open-source method of data storage and processing.</p>
<p>The game isn't stored on a centralized server or controlled by a central authority; it's a community-driven project, with members of the community powering the game and deciding on new features, updates, and other additions that affect the game.</p>
<p>As it's an open-source ecosystem like Bitcoin, changes such as the creation of new characters, potions, skins, and other in-game assets can be made by the community without the need for approval from the developers or creators of the game.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Blockchain Technology</strong></h3>
<p>Nine Chronicles is a blockchain-based game; every aspect of the game is entirely built on the <a href="https://github.com/planetarium/libplanet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Libplanet</a> blockchain, a distributed ledger technology used to create decentralized games that use a peer-to-peer network rather than a centralized server.</p>
<h3><strong>3. Play-to-earn (P2E)</strong></h3>
<p>The game makes it possible for players and miners to earn NFT collectibles, which they can trade with other players in the community.</p>
<h3><strong>4. Mining</strong></h3>
<p>Mining is another fantastic addition to the Nine Chronicles platform.</p>
<p>Gamers and miners contribute their computing power to the blockchain network to help verify data.</p>
<p>In return for the computing power that they contribute, they are rewarded 10 NCG tokens per block mined.</p>
<p>However, the block rewards get halved every 4 years, with the next halving happening by 2024, and the reward for each block mined will be reduced to 5 NCG tokens.</p>
<h3><strong>5. NCG (Nine Chronicles Gold)</strong></h3>
<p>Nine Chronicles Gold ($NCG) is the native currency of the Nine Chronicles ecosystem.</p>
<p>Players can use NCG to purchase items from other players, craft and upgrade powerful items, challenge other players, and accelerate growth.</p>
<p>Players need to stake NCG to receive items such as AP potions, hourglasses, and other limited consumables that are crucial for the character's growth acceleration.</p>
<p>Though staking NCG isn't necessary when you start playing, the game is designed so that NCG's needs are gradually increased as you progress through the game and achieve new levels.</p>
<p>Apart from mining, players can earn $NCG tokens by crafting and selling NFT items on the marketplace, by participating in the <a href="https://bit.ly/9c-eco-support" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ecosystem support program</a>, or through giveaways on Nine Chronicles' platforms.</p>
<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>
<p>Nine Chronicles is a fantastic game, with various amazing features that make the game a good prospect.</p>
<p>Though some levels of the game are yet to be launched, it's still a gaming project that you should look into, especially if you're looking to earn rewards.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/nine-chronicles-play-to-earn-on-a-decentralized-platform846-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forest Knight Play-to-Earn Game Review</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/forest-knight-play-to-earn-game-review841-2/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/forest-knight-play-to-earn-game-review841-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 19:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Forest Knight]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We all love the idea of making a few bucks while doing things we love and would even do for free. And if you've ever had the privilege of making money for writing, singing, watching a movie, or playing a video game on the internet, you know how amazing it feels. So if you're a gamer who plays games like...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all love the idea of making a few bucks while doing things we love and would even do for free.</p>
<p>And if you've ever had the privilege of making money for writing, singing, watching a movie, or playing a video game on the internet, you know how amazing it feels.</p>
<p>So if you're a gamer who plays games like crazy even if you have to invest hundreds of dollars to buy a weapon or subscribe for an in-game feature, then the idea of a play-to-earn game might sound interesting to you.</p>
<p>In This Article</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>What is the Forest Knight?</strong></li>
<li><strong>How to Earn in Forest Knight</strong></li>
<li><strong>How to Start Playing Forest Knight</strong></li>
<li><strong>Features of the Forest Knight</strong></li>
<li><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>And no, it's not just another case of &#8220;when you order GTA San Andreas from Wish,&#8221; as you might be wondering; the game you're about to learn about is Forest Knight.</p>
<p>a game that opens the doors of opportunity for gamers to earn rewards for both the money and time they invest in playing games.</p>
<p>Without further ado, here's all you need to know about Forest Knight.</p>
<h2><strong>What is Forest Knight?</strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.forestknight.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forest Knight</a> is a turn-based RPG adventure game that combines traditional gaming with play-to-earn features to create a blockchain game that allows players to monetize the time they spend playing games.</p>
<p>It's an NFT game that uses the free-to-play and play-to-earn gaming models to reward players with NFTs and cryptocurrencies, which they can sell or exchange for real cash.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Earn in Forest Knight</strong></h2>
<p>You play the game as Forest Knight and embark on daily missions, fight against other players in PvP mode, and go on adventures to defeat evil commanders so you can earn rewards and build your dream team of heroes.</p>
<p>As you progress through the game and complete missions, you’ll unlock heroes (NFT characters), all with their own unique strengths, weaknesses, and traits.</p>
<p>Your goal is to create a formidable team of heroes, and to achieve this, you can make your heroes more powerful by equipping them with the best weapons and other NFTs, which represent in-game assets.</p>
<p>As you progress through the game and unlock new in-game items such as heroes, weapons, skins, and pets, you can use these items to make your heroes more powerful or sell the items as NFTs on the <a href="https://opensea.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OpenSea NFT marketplace</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Start Playing Forest Knight</strong></h2>
<p>The game is available on Android devices and PCs and can be downloaded from the Google Play Store to play on an Android device or using an emulator if you're using a PC.</p>
<p>Meanwhile: <a href="https://jasper.ai?special=qUo64YY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jasper Al will help you create an NFT collection in few minutes</a></p>
<h2>Features of Forest Knight</h2>
<p>The game has a lot of amazing features that make it standout among other games. There are the PVE (Player vs. Enemy) and PVP (Player vs. Player) modes, which are set in a battleground scenery with adventurous missions in place.</p>
<p>Here are other amazing features of Forest Knight.</p>
<h3><strong>1. NFT Collectibles</strong></h3>
<p>The NFT feature is an integral part of the game.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.forestknight.io/gamrey" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Forest Knight NFTs</a> are unique in-game assets that represent heroes, weapons, pets, skins, and other in-game accessories.</p>
<p>These NFTs can be used to strengthen heroes, gain access to in-game benefits, exchanged for other items with other players, or sold on the NFT marketplace.</p>
<h3><strong>2. $KNIGHT Token</strong></h3>
<p>$KNIGHT is the governance currency of Forest Knight.</p>
<p>The Knight token is used to reward players for their in-game activities. Knight tokens can be used to purchase heroes, buy and sell land, be held for additional in-game incentives, be staked for rewards, etc.</p>
<p>Players who hold Knight tokens will not only earn in-game rewards but also have a say in the development of future projects in the Forest Knight ecosystem.</p>
<h3><strong>3. Free-to-play</strong></h3>
<p>While most games charge players for their participation, Forest Knight is a free-to-play NFT game, although you can purchase KNIGHT or in-game accessories to increase your chances of earning rewards in-game.</p>
<h3><strong>4. Play-to-earn</strong></h3>
<p>Unlike traditional games that charge gamers hundreds of dollars for in-game assets without any form of reward, Forest Knight has developed a mechanism that gives back to its community of gamers.</p>
<p>You earn rewards in KNIGHT and NFTs, which you can sell on a cryptocurrency exchange or trade on an NFT marketplace, respectively.</p>
<h4><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h4>
<p>Forest Knight combines blockchain technology with gaming to provide a rewarding experience for gamers.</p>
<p>It's not a game that can replace your 9–5 job, but the earning potential is impressive for a game you can even play for free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/forest-knight-play-to-earn-game-review841-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Axie Infinity?</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/what-is-axie-infinity825-2/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/what-is-axie-infinity825-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Axie Infinity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Various fantastic play-to-earn (P2E) games have been launched on blockchains in the gaming industry. These games have offered gamers the opportunity to earn rewards while doing what they love. In fact, with the emergence of P2E gaming, players no longer have to invest in video games without getting anything in return. They can now earn money from playing both the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Various fantastic play-to-earn (P2E) games have been launched on blockchains in the gaming industry.</p>
<p>These games have offered gamers the opportunity to earn rewards while doing what they love.</p>
<p>In fact, with the emergence of P2E gaming, players no longer have to invest in video games without getting anything in return. They can now earn money from playing both the games that they invested in and those they play for free.</p>
<p>At the very top of the list among these fantastic P2E games is Axie Infinity, the play-to-earn game that served as a source of income to both gamers and non-gamers during the COVID-19 pandemic in 2020.</p>
<p>In this article, you'll learn what Axie Infinity is all about and how you can earn money playing the NFT game.</p>
<h2>What is Axie Infinity?</h2>
<p>Axie Infinity is a Pokemon-themed NFT metaverse game based on the Ethereum blockchain and developed by Sky Mavis.</p>
<p>To play the game, you need &#8220;Axies&#8221;, which are NFT characters that you can collect or mint in order to grow, build, hunt for treasures, and go to battle with them.</p>
<p>Apart from the native game, the metaverse platform also serves as an ecosystem of NFT metaverse games, allowing users to create games on their virtual land using the Lunacia SDK.</p>
<p>In short, you can create your own metaverse game as long as you own a parcel of land on the Axie Infinity platform.</p>
<p>You can design your game using the Lunacia SDK, after which the game is saved as an NFT tradeable on the NFT marketplace.</p>
<p>For other users to play your game, they can locate your NFT land on the Axie Infinity map, click on it, and automatically gain access to your game.</p>
<h2>How to Get Started with Axie Infinity</h2>
<p>To play the game, you need to purchase three &#8220;Axies&#8221;, which are NFT characters that are used as pets to play the Axie Infinity game, and also farm Smooth Love Potions (SLP) , a token used to reward players in-game.</p>
<p>Here are things to do to start playing Axie Infinity.</p>
<p>1. Create a MetaMask wallet and fund it with (ETH) Ethereum tokens.</p>
<p>2. Go to the official Axie Infinity NFT marketplace or OpenSea to purchase three &#8216;Axies'.</p>
<p>3. Go to the official website and download the Axie Infinity game.</p>
<p>The app isn't yet available on the Playstore for mobile phones, so here are things to do to download the app on your mobile phone:</p>
<p>Go to https://axieinfinity.com/ and select &#8220;Play Now&#8221; in the upper right corner of the page.</p>
<p>Select &#8220;Android&#8221; and then click &#8220;install&#8221;.</p>
<p>Once you've installed the app, you're free to start growing, building, and hunting for treasures with your &#8220;Axies&#8221;, while you also earn SLP tokens in passive income for holding &#8220;Axies.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Amazing Features of Axie Infinity</h2>
<h3>1. Axie NFTs</h3>
<p>Axies are pets used to play Axie Infinity. They can be bred with SLP tokens or purchased on an NFT marketplace.</p>
<p>Axies come in different characteristics and base classes, and there are nine different base classes of axies in the Axie Infinity metaverse.</p>
<p>They are: plant, reptile, aqua, bird, beast, bug, mech, dusk, and dawn.</p>
<p>Each Axie belongs to one or two of these base classes and has four additional qualities in health, speed, skills, and morale with its base class.</p>
<p>One of the best perks of owning an Axie is that you can earn energy potions which can yield SLP tokens as a holder of an Axie NFT.</p>
<h3>2.Governance Tokens</h3>
<p>Axie Infinity Shards (AXS) and Smooth Love Potions (SLP) are the two native currencies of the Axie Infinity game and both have their specific usages in the Axie Infinity community.</p>
<p>The basic usecase of AXS is to allow you and other members of the community to participate in the decision-making process of running the Axie Infinity metaverse.</p>
<p>SLP, on the other hand, is used to breed &#8220;Axies&#8221;, though it is also used to reward players in-game.</p>
<p>Meanwhile: <a href="https://www.jasper.ai/?special=qUo64YY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">You can create NFTs in minutes with this software</a>.</p>
<h3>3. Create Your Own Metaverse Game</h3>
<p>If you've been dreaming of launching your own metaverse game, the Axie Infinity metaverse platform can make your dream come true.</p>
<p>Apart from the Axie Infinity game, Axie Infinity also serves as a metaverse ecosystem for gamers where people can launch their own games and invite other gamers to play the game, participate in competitions and win prizes.</p>
<h3>4. Access to a Wide Variety of Metaverse Gaming Experiences</h3>
<p>Another interesting feature of the Axie Infinity game is that you can get to play a variety of games and also interact with other gamers to create an immersive and interesting gaming experience.</p>
<h2>Should You Play Axie Infinity?</h2>
<p>If there are play-to-earn games that you should give a shot to, then Axie Infinity is one of them.</p>
<p>What Axie Infinity has achieved as a P2E metaverse game is still unmatched in the gaming industry.</p>
<p>In 2020, during the COVID-19 pandemic, playing Axie Infinity served as a source of income for Filipinos and other people around the world who couldn't go to work due to the lockdown caused by the pandemic.</p>
<p>Millions of Gamers have since adopted the game as not only a source of entertainment but also a means through which they can generate passive income.</p>
<p>Therefore, yes, you should play Axie Infinity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/what-is-axie-infinity825-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Galaxy Fight Club— A Free-To-Play Earning Opportunity For Gamers</title>
		<link>https://metaknow.org/galaxy-fight-club-a-free-to-play-money-making-opportunity-for-gamers745-2/</link>
					<comments>https://metaknow.org/galaxy-fight-club-a-free-to-play-money-making-opportunity-for-gamers745-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olusegun Kehinde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 16:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gamefi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Galaxy fight club]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://metaknow.org/?p=745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imagine playing an NFT metaverse game but with your own NFT vs NFTs from other collections. That's exactly the game-changing approach that Galaxy Fight Club has to offer to the metaverse's interoperability challenge, bringing NFT communities and gaming communities together and making gameplay more entertaining and interactive. The NFT game is the first Cross-Intellectual Property (Cross-IP) game with an opportunity...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Imagine playing an NFT metaverse game but with your own NFT vs NFTs from other collections.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That's exactly the game-changing approach that <a href="https://galaxyfightclub.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Galaxy Fight Club</a> has to offer to the metaverse's interoperability challenge, bringing NFT communities and gaming communities together and making gameplay more entertaining and interactive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The NFT game is the first Cross-Intellectual Property (Cross-IP) game with an opportunity for players to use their digital collectibles from other collections in Galaxy Fight Club.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Table of Contents</span></p>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>What is Galaxy Fight Club (GFC)?</b></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Mission of Galaxy Fight Club.</b></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Galaxy Fight Club gameplay.</b></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Play-to-earn: How to Earn Rewards in Galaxy Fight Club.</b></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li aria-level="1"><b>Interesting Features of Galaxy Fight Club</b></li>
<li aria-level="1"><strong>How To Start Playing Galaxy Fight Club</strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>What is Galaxy Fight Club (GFC)?</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Galaxy Fight Club (GFC) is the first cross-intellectual property (cross-IP), cross-platform game in the metaverse that allows holders of various NFTs from different collections to compete in the GFC game.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The cross-platform (Cross-IP) feature allows players to use NFTs from other collections in the GFC game.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GFC is an opportunity for gamers to bring their NFT game characters from different collections together on one gaming platform.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<h2><b>Mission of Galaxy Fight Club</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Galaxy Fight Club launched in late 2021 with the main objective of bringing a new dimension of play to the gaming space. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With their cross-platform, Cross-IP feature, the team aims to make interoperability in the metaverse a reality by making it possible for players to bring their avatars and other digital assets to battle other players and earn rewards while doing so.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Galaxy Fight Club Gameplay</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GFC is a mobile PvP (Player vs. Player) and MOBA (Multiplayer Online Battle Arena) game in which players compete against each other to defeat the opposing team.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The game has four combat models: 3v3, Classic Death Match (1v1), Battle Royale, and Tournament mode.</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>3 vs. 3</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each team in the 3 vs. 3 mode consists of 3 players. And the 3v3 game lasts for about five minutes, with the first team that earns 20 points or scores 20 kills winning the battle.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>Classic Death Match (1v1)</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a classic death match, players enter the battle arena and fight each other. The first player to earn 10 points or score 10 kills will then win the battle.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>Battle Royale (Last Man Standing)</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">10 players face-off in a free-for-all fight in which the last man standing wins.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>Tournament mode</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tournament mode is the 3v3 mode but players have to battle in more than one match as this mode comes with rounds leading up to a final match.</span></li>
</ol>
<p>Also read: <a href="https://metaknow.org/best-nft-games-for-android-in-2022740-2/">Best NFT Games For Android in 2022</a></p>
<h2><b>Play-to-earn: How to Earn Rewards in Galaxy Fight Club</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">GFC makes it possible for both those who don't invest and those who invest in the Galaxy Fight Club NFTs to earn from the game.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those who are using the free-to-play model will be given a default base character they can use in battle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While those who pay for a GFC NFT will have better characters, fights, keys and other privileges such as receiving between 5 and 15 $GCOIN (GFC's native token) every day in passive income.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To earn money in Galaxy Fight Club, players need to win battles so they can win keys to open lootboxes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are three types of keys in Galaxy Fight Club, and the type that a player can win depends on the NFT character he owns.</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>Gold keys</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For players who own an NFT from Galaxy Fight Club's collection, gold keys are available. A Gen 1 or 2 Galaxy fighter, or at least equipped with a weapon or armor from GFC's NFT collection, if the player isn't using an NFT from GFC's collection.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>Partner keys</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Partner keys are for players using an NFT from a collection that is partnered with Galaxy Fight Club.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<h4><b>Silver keys</b></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Available for free to players who are playing with a default base character.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When players win keys and lootboxes, they can either sell the lootboxes, or open them and collect rare in-game items (NFTs), which they can use in-game or sell on NFT marketplaces.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other ways to earn rewards are by forging and selling weapons, renting out fighters, and creating and selling second-generation fighters.</span></p>
<h2><b>Interesting Features of Galaxy Fight Club</b></h2>
<h3><b>1. Cross Intellectual Property (Cross-IP) Game</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This interoperable feature makes the gaming experience more entertaining.</span></p>
<p><b style="color: #1d1f20; font-size: 1.563em;">2. Free to play + Play-to-earn</b></p>
<p>Players do not need to invest in the game before playing, and they can still earn rewards for playing the game.</p>
<h3><b>3. Passive income opportunities</b></h3>
<p>Holders of Galaxy Fight Club NFTs can earn passive income in $GCOIN tokens.</p>
<h3><b>How To Start Playing Galaxy Fight Club</b></h3>
<p>Download the app on the PlayStore on your Android device, sign up and start playing for rewards.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://metaknow.org/galaxy-fight-club-a-free-to-play-money-making-opportunity-for-gamers745-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
