<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" 
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	> 

	<channel>
		<title>GameFi 2022 | NFTandGameFi GameFi 202</title>
		<atom:link href="https://nftandgamefi.com/category/gamefi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/category/gamefi</link>
		<description>The Definitive Hub for NFT and GameFi News</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 14:16:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod> hourly </sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency> 1 </sy:updateFrequency>
		<atom:link rel="hub" href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
		<generator>GN Publisher v1.5.8 https://wordpress.org/plugins/gn-publisher/</generator>

		<item>
			<title>Do-it-to-Earn: the new era in crypto gaming</title>
			<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/08/05/do-it-to-earn-crypto/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 19:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[NFT and GameFi Team]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://nftandgamefi.com/?p=4949</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Ah, the ever-evolving world of cryptocurrencies, where you can witness innovations popping up faster than...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Screenshot-2022-05-21-at-4.06.59-PM.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Ah, the ever-evolving world of cryptocurrencies, where you can witness innovations popping up faster than you can say &#8220;Satoshi Nakamoto.&#8221; Blockchain tech, the magical elixir behind it all, promises to revolutionize finance with its cheaper, faster, and more accessible services – hallelujah, financial freedom, here we come!</p>



<p>But hold on, folks, that&#8217;s not all! Brace yourselves for the next-level brilliance – drum roll, please – the one, the only, the mind-blowing concept of &#8220;Do-it-to-Earn&#8221;! Yes, you heard it right, now you can earn crypto just by doing stuff. Is this some kind of virtual dream? Nope, it&#8217;s real, and it&#8217;s here to rock your world.</p>



<p>So, what is this &#8220;Do-it-to-Earn&#8221; sorcery? Well, it&#8217;s all in the name, my dear friends. You do stuff, and voilà! Crypto starts raining down on you like confetti at a crypto party. And guess what? These activities can be as random as a toddler&#8217;s doodle. Play games, run like your life depends on it (well, maybe your crypto wallet&#8217;s life), and even learn stuff – yep, education pays now!</p>



<p>For all the non-techies out there, this whole Do-it-to-Earn jazz might sound as perplexing as trying to explain quantum physics to a houseplant. Fear not, for we&#8217;ve got you covered with a blog tailored just for you! We&#8217;ll unravel the secrets of the various Do-it-to-Earn types and show you how to swim in the crypto-rich waters without drowning in confusion.</p>



<h2 id="the-birth-of-gamefi-and-p2e" class="wp-block-heading">The Birth of GameFi and P2E</h2>



<p>The genius idea of GameFi (yep, it&#8217;s a thing now) came to life when gaming met cryptocurrencies, and they hit it off like a match made in the blockchain heaven. That&#8217;s when Play-to-Earn, or P2E for the cool kids, strutted onto the scene. Picture this: you play games, and in return, you get rewarded with digital goodies like NFTs (fancy collectibles) or cryptocurrencies. It&#8217;s like getting paid for having a blast – sign me up!</p>



<p>In these P2E games, you&#8217;ll find all sorts of treats. Some have in-game tokens, think of them as the golden coins of the digital realm, like AXS and SLP in the ever-popular Axie Infinity. And that&#8217;s not all, it gets even better – there are Pokémon-inspired creatures (NFTs, to be exact) to add to your collection. It&#8217;s like your wildest childhood dreams coming true, but with crypto sprinkled on top.</p>



<p>These P2E games aren&#8217;t just some fly-by-night scheme. They are all about creating sustainable economies, balancing the value of their precious NFTs and in-game tokens like a master chef balancing flavors in a five-star restaurant. So, buckle up, my fellow gamers, because this is just the beginning of the P2E adventure, and we&#8217;re in for a wild, profitable ride!</p>



<h2 id="what-are-play-to-earn-games" class="wp-block-heading">What Are Play-to-Earn Games?</h2>



<p>P2E games love to spoil their players with NFTs or cryptocurrencies as rewards, and guess what? You can trade these digital treasures for other valuable assets or even convert them into good ol&#8217; fiat currencies through exchanges and marketplaces.</p>



<p>But before you dive headfirst into this money-making extravaganza, get your wallets ready. Yep, these games demand an upfront investment, and it can be quite the chunk of change depending on factors like the token&#8217;s value and how badly folks want in. For example, during the AXS token peak, new players had to cough up around $1,000 just to join the party!</p>



<h2 id="is-there-a-game-that-pays-real-money" class="wp-block-heading">Is there a game that pays real money?</h2>



<p>Now, here comes the big question – can you find a game that dishes out real, tangible money? Well, well, well, plenty of P2E games are generous enough to shower you with rewards in the form of cryptocurrencies or NFTs, which you can happily convert into fiat currencies. But, and there&#8217;s a &#8220;but,&#8221; no blockchain-based game is going to hand you actual fiat on a virtual platter.</p>



<p>Why, you ask? Simple. Paying in fiat currency would spoil the party for the in-game token, and we can&#8217;t have that. The token is the lifeblood of the game&#8217;s economy, ensuring things stay sustainable and exciting. So, while the game won&#8217;t stuff your pockets with paper bills, rest assured you&#8217;ll be swimming in a sea of crypto-riches!</p>



<h2 id="what-are-play-to-earn-nft-games" class="wp-block-heading">What are Play-to-Earn NFT games?</h2>



<p>Play-to-earn NFT games are a fascinating gaming trend that introduces a new way for players to engage and potentially earn money. In these games, participants begin by purchasing an NFT, which could be a weapon, character, or avatar, as a ticket to enter the virtual world. Just like other play-to-earn games, players can make profits from their gaming efforts. However, the rewards are often distributed in the form of NFTs, which require players to utilize a marketplace to convert them into cash.</p>



<h2 id="examples-of-play-to-earn-games" class="wp-block-heading">Examples of Play-to-Earn games</h2>



<p>The play-to-earn model, initially popularized by Axie Infinity, has given rise to numerous blockchain-based games incorporating this unique framework. Among the top five games following this approach are:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Axie Infinity: </strong>In this game, players collect and create NFTs representing adorable axolotl-inspired digital pets called Axies.</li>



<li><strong>Decentraland: </strong>This NFT-centric blockchain game allows players to construct their own virtual environments, explore other users&#8217; habitats, and participate in various activities.</li>



<li><strong>Gods Unchained: </strong>Offering a free-to-play experience, this competitive trading card game employs NFTs to enhance card ownership and value.</li>



<li><strong>Splinterlands: </strong>Another captivating <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/06/23/slinterlands-play2earn-launches-gaming-channel/">blockchain-based trading card game</a> where players can trade, strategize, and compete to earn valuable NFTs.</li>



<li><strong>The Sandbox: </strong>Within this virtual world, players can unleash their creativity by building, owning, and monetizing their unique gaming experiences, all based on NFT ownership.</li>
</ol>



<p>Read also: <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/">Best NFT games to Play in 2023</a></p>



<h2 id="what-are-move-to-earn-games" class="wp-block-heading">What Are Move-to-Earn Games?</h2>



<p>Move-to-earn games represent an innovative fusion of the fitness and cryptocurrency industries, where players are incentivized to engage in physical activities such as working out, walking, and running to earn cryptocurrency rewards. These games leverage technology to track the movement of players and distribute crypto rewards accordingly. However, to prevent excessive exploitation, the rewards are usually capped on a daily basis, encouraging participants to maintain their regular fitness routines.</p>



<p>One exciting aspect of move-to-earn games is the incorporation of Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) in the form of sports accessories like sneakers. To participate in these games, players are required to acquire at least one of these NFTs, which adds a unique and collectible element to the experience. By merging physical activity and blockchain technology, move-to-earn games have created a novel and engaging way for individuals to prioritize their well-being while exploring the world of cryptocurrencies.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="4964" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/08/05/do-it-to-earn-crypto/move-to-earn-app-earnings-1024x577/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/move-to-earn-app-earnings-1024x577-1.png?fit=1024%2C577&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,577" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="move-to-earn-app-earnings-1024&#215;577" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/move-to-earn-app-earnings-1024x577-1.png?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/move-to-earn-app-earnings-1024x577-1.png?fit=1024%2C577&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="1024" height="577" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/move-to-earn-app-earnings-1024x577-1.png?resize=1024%2C577&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4964"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2 id="examples-of-popular-move-to-earn-games" class="wp-block-heading">Examples of popular Move-to-Earn  games:</h2>



<ul>
<li>Sweatcoin (SWEAT)</li>



<li>STEPN</li>



<li>Genopets</li>



<li>Wirtual</li>
</ul>



<p>Find out more about the best Move-to-Earn games <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/05/05/move-to-earn-games/">by following this link</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4968" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/08/05/do-it-to-earn-crypto/image-34/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image.png?fit=1280%2C691&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1280,691" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image.png?fit=300%2C162&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image.png?fit=1024%2C553&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="553" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image.png?resize=1024%2C553&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4968"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Image source: <a href="https://hackernoon.com/move-to-earn-the-latest-crypto-sensation-that-rewards-users-for-engaging-in-physical-activities">Hackernoon</a></figcaption></figure>



<h2 id="what-are-learn-to-earn-games" class="wp-block-heading">What are Learn-to-Earn games?</h2>



<p>Learn-to-earn crypto games represent a captivating convergence between the education industry and cryptocurrencies. In this model, users are incentivized to deepen their understanding of specific cryptocurrencies and how they function. As a reward for their learning efforts, users receive payouts in the form of the underlying cryptocurrency, encouraging them to explore and engage with it firsthand.</p>



<p>The premise behind learn-to-earn games is to educate users about the intricacies of various cryptocurrencies while providing them with a practical experience of using these digital assets. By combining education and cryptocurrency incentives, these games offer a valuable opportunity for individuals to expand their knowledge of the crypto space while also gaining a tangible stake in the currencies they learn about.</p>



<h2 id="where-can-i-learn-to-earn-crypto" class="wp-block-heading">Where can I learn to earn crypto?</h2>



<p><strong><a href="https://letmespeak.org/">LetMeSpeak</a>: </strong>Earn while you learn English! This learn-to-earn app incentivizes users to master English with economic benefits and NFT rewards. Developed by language experts, it offers vocabulary expansion, grammar practice, and speaking exercises, claiming 5x efficiency. Start earning LSTARs and upgrade NFT characters. iOS and Web available, Android coming soon. No investment option also provided. Future expansion to other languages planned.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img data-attachment-id="4979" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/08/05/do-it-to-earn-crypto/image-2-10/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-2.png?fit=498%2C630&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="498,630" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-2.png?fit=237%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-2.png?fit=498%2C630&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-2.png?resize=351%2C444&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4979"  width="351" height="444"  sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure></div>


<p>A few well-known crypto entities offer this kind of incentive, including some of the big&nbsp;CEXs.</p>



<p>Coinbase Earn and Binance Learn are educational initiatives offered by popular cryptocurrency exchanges that provide users with an opportunity to learn about various cryptocurrencies while earning rewards.</p>



<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learning-rewards"><strong>Coinbase Earn </strong>offers</a> users the chance to watch animated videos or read articles about specific cryptocurrencies. Afterward, they complete quizzes to test their knowledge and understanding. Upon successfully completing the quizzes, users receive crypto rewards directly deposited into their Coinbase account. The rewards may not make users wealthy, but it&#8217;s a convenient and relatively low-time investment to learn and earn in the crypto space.</li>



<li>On the other hand, <a href="https://academy.binance.com/en/learn-and-earn"><strong>Binance Learn</strong></a> is available exclusively to users who already have a Binance account. This aspect serves as a perk or reward for being a Binance account holder. Similar to Coinbase Earn, users watch videos and take quizzes to enhance their understanding of different cryptocurrencies. However, the reward system differs slightly. Instead of receiving the crypto tokens directly, users are issued vouchers for the respective cryptocurrencies they have learned about. It&#8217;s important to note that these vouchers have a limited validity period of 14 days, prompting users to take action and redeem their earned rewards within the given timeframe.</li>



<li><strong>Phemex</strong>, a centralized exchange, previously <a href="https://phemex.com/learn-crypto">introduced a learn-to-earn feature</a>, allowing users to earn rewards while expanding their cryptocurrency knowledge. However, as of the current moment, the platform has announced the temporary suspension of the reward element due to a restructuring of its bonus program. This serves as a reminder that rewards programs, despite their appeal, can be subject to changes or even temporary suspension when companies need to make adjustments in response to various factors. Flexibility and awareness are essential in navigating the dynamic landscape of cryptocurrency exchanges and their associated incentives.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.gate.io/learn"><strong>Gate Learn</strong> presents</a> a remarkable opportunity for skilled creators to capitalize on their knowledge and expertise while earning cryptocurrency rewards. By submitting engaging, informative, and original articles on a topic of their choice, users stand a chance to receive up to 150 USDT per article. The process is simple and involves crafting compelling content, which is then reviewed by the Gate.io team. The submitted content is assessed based on various criteria, including accuracy and creativity. Higher-ranked articles have a greater likelihood of being published and subsequently rewarded with higher incentives. Gate Learn&#8217;s platform thus serves as a platform that values and rewards knowledge-sharing, empowering creators to contribute to the community while earning crypto for their valuable insights and contributions.</li>



<li><strong>Nexus</strong> is a <a href="https://chaindebrief.com/nexus/">Learn and Earn program by Chain Debrief</a> that enables users to receive tokens while learning about a cryptocurrency project</li>
</ol>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4970" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/08/05/do-it-to-earn-crypto/image-1-10/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-1.png?fit=1280%2C720&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image-1" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-1.png?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-1.png?fit=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/image-1.png?resize=1024%2C576&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4970"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2 id="do-to-earn-games-forecasts" class="wp-block-heading">Do-to-Earn games forecasts</h2>



<p>The future of Do-It-To-Earn blockchain apps looks extremely promising, as this incentive-driven model continues to find its way into various industries. Already successfully implemented in gaming, fitness, and learning, it holds the potential to expand into new sectors such as entertainment, food, and health.</p>



<p>For example, integrating the Do-It-To-Earn model with the entertainment industry could offer users rewards for watching movies and series, creating an engaging and interactive experience for viewers.</p>



<p>One of the key strengths of this model is its ability to reward users for everyday activities, making it appealing to a broad audience. Activities like playing games, exercising, and learning are not only incentivized, but they are also enjoyable, further increasing their appeal to a wide user base.</p>



<p>Moreover, there is an exciting opportunity to explore the integration of Do-It-To-Earn apps with the metaverse, a virtual shared space where users can interact, create, and participate in various experiences. This integration could open up new dimensions for engagement and rewards within the virtual world.</p>



<p>In summary, the future of Do-It-To-Earn blockchain apps holds immense potential for growth, innovation, and widespread adoption across multiple industries, making it an exciting trend to watch as it continues to shape the digital landscape.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/08/05/do-it-to-earn-crypto/">Do-it-to-Earn: the new era in crypto gaming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com">NFTandGameFi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Top 5 NFT Games to Watch this July</title>
			<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 07:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[NFT and GameFi Team]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://nftandgamefi.com/?p=4587</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Get your popcorn ready, because we&#8217;ve got a list that’s hotter than the July sun:...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/affyn.png" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Get your popcorn ready, because we&#8217;ve got a list that’s hotter than the July sun: the top five NFT games that you just can&#8217;t afford to miss this month. We will dive into the digital madness and see who&#8217;s going to rock the metaverse. This July, the heat isn&#8217;t just rising in the atmosphere; it&#8217;s also soaring in the realm of blockchain gaming. So, let&#8217;s have a closer look at what the gaming industry has prepared for us this month.</p>



<h2 id="1-affyn-the-rising-star-of-play-to-earn" class="wp-block-heading">1. Affyn: The Rising Star of Play-to-Earn</h2>



<p>First up, we have <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/06/20/affyn-game-review/">Affyn play-to-earn (P2E)</a> game that&#8217;s so ambitious, it might have bitten off more than it can chew. This P2E prodigy is set to give Pokémon GO a run for its money with its geolocation-based gameplay. You don&#8217;t just play Affyn, you live it, as they proudly claim. The team seems to have a thing for being real, as their native token, $FYN, isn&#8217;t just confined to the digital world but can be used to purchase real-world goods and services. That&#8217;s right, you can grab your morning latte with your gaming tokens. How&#8217;s that for a game-changer?</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-7389952621846029"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7389952621846029"
     data-ad-slot="2695566356"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>But wait, there&#8217;s more. Despite a few high-profile departures, the Affyn team is exuding an air of confidence that&#8217;s contagious. They&#8217;re committed to a free-to-play model and are boldly tackling sustainability issues prevalent in the P2E genre. So, with grand plans for mainstream adoption and a unique approach to sustainability, Affyn could be the next P2E sensation. Or it could be an overhyped dud. Only time will tell​.</p>



<h2 id="2-vulcanverse-the-greco-roman-metaverse" class="wp-block-heading">2. VulcanVerse: The Greco-Roman Metaverse</h2>



<p>Next on our list is <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/06/13/vulcanverse-review/">VulcanVerse</a>, a next-gen blockchain-based MMORPG that&#8217;s decided to time-travel back to the Greco-Roman era for some inspiration. Featuring world-building and quests, player-owned lands, and NFT-based game assets, VulcanVerse is all set to give Julius Caesar a complex.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4591" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/vulcanverse/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/vulcanverse.png?fit=1172%2C702&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1172,702" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="vulcanverse" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/vulcanverse.png?fit=300%2C180&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/vulcanverse.png?fit=1024%2C613&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="613" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/vulcanverse.png?resize=1024%2C613&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4591"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>This game&#8217;s got a star team including Fighting Fantasy authors and famous fantasy artist Frank Frazetta. The game is in beta, but that hasn&#8217;t stopped them from inking strategic partnerships with the likes of AAG Ventures, Animoca Brands, and MetaRing. But like any good Greek tragedy, there&#8217;s a twist. VulcanVerse is grappling with technical issues, player adoption, and regulatory uncertainty. Will VulcanVerse rise like a phoenix or go down like the Titanic? Stay tuned!</p>



<h2 id="3-derby-stars-the-dark-horse-of-nft-gaming" class="wp-block-heading">3. Derby Stars: The Dark Horse of NFT Gaming</h2>



<p>Switching gears from the ancient world to the racetrack, <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/06/12/derby-starts-review/">Derby Stars</a> is an upcoming play-to-earn horse racing game that&#8217;s hoping to win the Triple Crown of the NFT metaverse. Developed on the Polygon blockchain, this game gives players the chance to own, breed, and race NFT horses, which has all the thrills of owning a real horse without the mess.</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s not all sunshine and roses. Derby Stars is still in the early stages of development and has to navigate potential technical issues and regulatory changes. Will Derby Stars be the Secretariat of the NFT gaming world, or will it end up as an also-ran? The race is on.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4592" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/test_1655193383cvw4qhdwo1_1655193634qgmccaoxqc/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/test_1655193383cvW4QHdWo1_1655193634QGmcCaOxqc.webp?fit=1600%2C900&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1600,900" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="test_1655193383cvW4QHdWo1_1655193634QGmcCaOxqc" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/test_1655193383cvW4QHdWo1_1655193634QGmcCaOxqc.webp?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/test_1655193383cvW4QHdWo1_1655193634QGmcCaOxqc.webp?fit=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/test_1655193383cvW4QHdWo1_1655193634QGmcCaOxqc.webp?resize=1024%2C576&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4592"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2 id="4-ascenders-climbing-to-new-heights" class="wp-block-heading">4. Ascenders: Climbing to New Heights</h2>



<p>Ascenders, an open-world action RPG, is breaking the mold in blockchain gaming. With its player-driven economy, dual token system, land ownership, and specialized roles, <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/06/20/ascenders-review/">Ascenders</a> offers a gaming experience like no other. Players can explore diverse terrains, compete in dungeons, and build their own in-game economy. Despite the challenges, if Ascenders can foster a lively community and continue refining its features, it could be a game-changer in the blockchain gaming industry.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4593" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/ascenders-2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/ascenders.jpeg?fit=1200%2C720&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1200,720" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="ascenders" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/ascenders.jpeg?fit=300%2C180&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/ascenders.jpeg?fit=1024%2C614&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="614" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/ascenders.jpeg?resize=1024%2C614&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4593"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2 id="5-banger-games-the-hero-in-the-blockchain-gaming-wild-west" class="wp-block-heading">5. Banger Games: The Hero in the Blockchain Gaming Wild West?</h2>



<p>Last but not least, we have <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/06/08/banger-games-review/">Banger Games</a>, the audacious newcomer that&#8217;s aiming to save the day in the wildwest of blockchain gaming. With a cool €10 million in their saddlebag, they&#8217;re planning to build the first gaming hub to aggregate players&#8217; experiences across multiple games. Banger Games&#8217; vision is to create a unified gaming universe, breaking down the walled-gardens of the gaming industry. With a shared currency and economy and the introduction of automated SMART Tournaments, Banger Games might just be the rugged hero we need in this volatile gaming universe.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="4595" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/banger-games/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/Banger-Games.png?fit=1305%2C553&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1305,553" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Banger-Games" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/Banger-Games.png?fit=300%2C127&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/Banger-Games.png?fit=1024%2C434&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="434" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/Banger-Games.png?resize=1024%2C434&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4595"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<h2 id="the-wild-ride-of-nft-gaming" class="wp-block-heading">The Wild Ride of NFT Gaming</h2>



<p>As we pull in the reins on this exhilarating journey through the most promising NFT games this July, it&#8217;s clear that the gaming landscape is evolving at a breakneck pace. From Affyn&#8217;s trailblazing vision to Banger Games&#8217; audacious ambitions, we&#8217;re witnessing a revolution that could redefine gaming as we know it.</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-7389952621846029"
     crossorigin="anonymous"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7389952621846029"
     data-ad-slot="2695566356"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>Sure, there&#8217;s risk, and the road to success is as unpredictable as a stampede. But one thing&#8217;s for sure: the rewards could be monumental. So, whether you&#8217;re a player, a developer, an investor, or a curious bystander, keep your eyes trained on the horizon. The future of gaming is unfolding right here, right now, and it&#8217;s a wild, thrilling ride you don&#8217;t want to miss.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/07/03/nft-games-list/">Top 5 NFT Games to Watch this July</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com">NFTandGameFi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Top Performing Countries for Your GameFi Marketing Strategy</title>
			<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/05/18/web3-gaming-countries/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 19:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[NFT and GameFi Team]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://nftandgamefi.com/?p=4181</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[Get ready to dive into the decentralized world of gaming as we unpack the intriguing...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/The-Gamer-Way-Can-Web3-Games-Ignite-Mass-Adoption-or-Will-Gaming-Greatness-Get-Lost-in-the-Web3-Hype-1.webp" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>Get ready to dive into the decentralized world of gaming as we unpack the intriguing findings of CoinGecko&#8217;s recent study. Taking us on a journey from 2021 to 2023, the research presents an engaging exploration of the global web3 gaming, also known as GameFi, trends. Harnessing the power of Google Trends data, the study unravels the evolving dynamics of the global GameFi landscape. Let&#8217;s delve into the most captivating takeaways, organized into key points for your easy understanding.</p>



<p>Read also: <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/03/01/companies-invest-in-web3/">Traditional Companies Are Bullish On Web3 Tech</a></p>



<h3 id="1-the-forefront-of-gamefi-leading-countries-and-regions" class="wp-block-heading">1. The Forefront of GameFi: Leading Countries and Regions</h3>



<p>CoinGecko&#8217;s study underscores that nine nations are leading the GameFi revolution— the <strong><em>Philippines, Nigeria, Pakistan, Singapore, Vietnam, South Korea, Hong Kong, China, and the UAE</em></strong>. These countries have consistently secured a place in the top 15 for web3 gaming-related searches over the past three years.</p>







<h3 id="2-southeast-asia-a-dominant-force-in-web3-gaming" class="wp-block-heading">2. Southeast Asia: A Dominant Force in Web3 Gaming</h3>



<p>Southeast Asia, particularly the Philippines, Singapore, and Vietnam, is a significant player in the global GameFi arena. Although the number of Southeast Asian countries within the top 15 fluctuated over the three years, their presence remained prominent.</p>



<h3 id="3-consistent-interest-from-east-asia" class="wp-block-heading">3. Consistent Interest from East Asia</h3>



<p>South Korea, Hong Kong, and China from East Asia have displayed consistent interest in web3 gaming. Their position in the top tier of GameFi interest underscores the growing popularity of this phenomenon in this region.</p>



<h3 id="4-south-asia-fluctuating-yet-significant" class="wp-block-heading">4. South Asia: Fluctuating yet Significant</h3>



<p>Although fluctuating, South Asia, and notably Pakistan, has displayed significant interest in web3 gaming. The number of South Asian representatives among the top 15 most interested countries varies, but their presence continues to be notable.</p>



<h3 id="5-web3-gaming-interest-rankings-in-2023" class="wp-block-heading">5. Web3 Gaming Interest Rankings in 2023</h3>



<p>CoinGecko’s research reveals that in 2023, the Philippines remains at the top of the list of countries most interested in web3 gaming. Close behind are Nigeria, Pakistan, and Singapore, which have all improved their rankings. South Korea too has climbed up the rankings, surpassing China and Hong Kong.</p>



<h3 id="6-rising-stars-and-fading-lights-in-2023" class="wp-block-heading">6. Rising Stars and Fading Lights in 2023</h3>



<p>The report highlights that the Netherlands has emerged as the leading European nation in web3 gaming in 2023. New entrants to the top 15 include Kenya, Lebanon, and Sri Lanka. On the other hand, Vietnam, China, and the UAE experienced a decrease in their web3 gaming interest.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="4182" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/05/18/web3-gaming-countries/image-19/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-19.png?fit=890%2C919&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="890,919" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image-19" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-19.png?fit=291%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-19.png?fit=890%2C919&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="890" height="919" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-19.png?resize=890%2C919&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4182"  sizes="(max-width: 890px) 100vw, 890px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/">Coingecko</a></figcaption></figure>



<h3 id="7-fluctuating-web3-gaming-interest-trends" class="wp-block-heading">7. Fluctuating Web3 Gaming Interest Trends</h3>



<p>The study presents a complex picture of fluctuating interest in web3 gaming from 2021 to 2023. Countries such as Pakistan, South Korea, Kenya, and Sri Lanka displayed consistent yearly growth, while others like Singapore, China, Thailand, and Venezuela have seen a decline in interest.</p>



<h4 id="conclusion" class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h4>



<p>CoinGecko’s research paints a fascinating picture of the evolving landscape of web3 gaming globally. The study underscores the growing interest in GameFi across different countries and regions, signifying the increasing adoption and acceptance of blockchain technologies worldwide. The insights offer a helpful guide for developers, investors, and gamers alike, aiding them to navigate the exciting world of web3 gaming.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/05/18/web3-gaming-countries/">Top Performing Countries for Your GameFi Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com">NFTandGameFi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Artificial intelligence seems to be the new era in GameFi &#8211; a brief overview</title>
			<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/01/31/gamefi-ai-2023/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 20:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[NFT and GameFi Team]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://nftandgamefi.com/?p=3504</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[In 2023, the integration of AI and gaming is likely to continue to advance and...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/gamefi-and-ai.png" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>In 2023, the integration of AI and gaming is likely to continue to advance and become even more prevalent. AI technology can enhance gaming experiences by providing smarter opponents, more immersive environments, and personalized recommendations. Additionally, AI can also help improve game development and testing, making the process more efficient and cost-effective. However, it&#8217;s also important to consider the potential ethical implications of AI in gaming, such as the creation of addictive or biased games.</p>



<h2 id="how-is-ai-related-to-gamefi" class="wp-block-heading">How is AI related to GameFi?</h2>



<p>AI is involved in gaming through several ways:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Game AI: </strong>AI algorithms are used to control non-player characters, enemies, and other game elements to make the gaming experience more challenging and interactive.</li>



<li><strong>Game Recommendation: </strong>AI algorithms analyze player behavior and preferences to recommend games that they are likely to enjoy.</li>



<li><strong>Game Design and Development:</strong> AI tools can be used to optimize game design, testing, and quality assurance, helping game developers to create better games more efficiently.</li>



<li><strong>Game Analytics: </strong>AI-powered analytics can provide valuable insights into player behavior, enabling game developers to make data-driven decisions about how to improve their games.</li>
</ol>



<p>Overall, AI is transforming the gaming industry by providing new opportunities for innovation and improving the gaming experience for players.</p>



<h2 id="ai-powered-gamefi-projects-2023" class="wp-block-heading">AI-powered GameFi projects &#8211; 2023</h2>



<p>Here are some AI-powered gaming projects that have been developed or are in development:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>AlphaGo</strong> &#8211; a game AI that defeated the world champion in the game of Go.</li>



<li><strong>OpenAI Dota 2</strong> &#8211; an AI-powered opponent that can play Dota 2, one of the most popular multiplayer online battle arena games.</li>



<li><strong>Ludobots</strong> &#8211; a platform that allows developers to build AI agents that can play any game.</li>



<li><strong>GameGAN</strong> &#8211; a generative adversarial network (GAN) that can generate game scenes and environments in a way that is indistinguishable from human-made ones.</li>



<li><strong>AI Dungeon</strong> &#8211; a text-based adventure game powered by AI, allowing players to explore and interact with a vast and unpredictable world.</li>



<li><strong>Reinforcement Learning in First Person Shooter games</strong> &#8211; AI algorithms that can learn to play first-person shooter games like Doom or Unreal Tournament by trial and error.</li>
</ol>



<p>These are just a few examples of the many AI-powered gaming projects that exist. As AI technology continues to advance, it is likely that we will see even more innovative and exciting AI-powered gaming projects in the future.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2023/01/31/gamefi-ai-2023/">Artificial intelligence seems to be the new era in GameFi &#8211; a brief overview</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com">NFTandGameFi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>Chainers Review &#8211; Free-To-Play NFT Game For Degens</title>
			<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/12/23/chainers-review/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 21:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[NFT and GameFi Team]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://nftandgamefi.com/?p=3333</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[New free-to-play NFT game&nbsp;Chainers&nbsp;has enjoyed a great start to life in the metaverse following its...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/FkbgQGWXkAMcvsz-1.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>New free-to-play <a href="https://chainers.io/free-nfts?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=nft&amp;utm_campaign=gamefi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NFT game&nbsp;Chainers</a>&nbsp;has enjoyed a great start to life in the metaverse following its offer of daily free NFTs for all players. Chainers players have been picking up their free digital gifts and using them to explore the diverse and expansive Chainers metaverse world, customizing their characters, homes, surroundings and more! Many <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/01/11/5-nft-blockchain-games-that-are-set-to-moon-in-gamefi/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blockchain games</a> to date have been underwhelming, with a high-cost threshold and with transaction fees, plus lengthy development time before the game is actually playable. Chainers is different – the project is very far down the runway, with players already playing and enjoying the game every day, while the concept of cost-free signup and free NFTs is encouraging thousands more players to try it out.</p>



<p>Chainers is a browser-based metaverse NFT game powered <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/11/09/oneplanet-to-provide-polygon-dedicated-launchpad-services/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">by Polygon</a> that aims to provide players with a fully immersive gaming experience with no requirement to download anything. The free-to-start game is based on player ownership and focuses on creating a sustainable creative economy while providing endless customization possibilities. Typically, metaverse games struggle in their early stages because there is no community to help build the ecosystem.&nbsp;Chainers is different, with more than 50,000 artists, musicians, designers and developers already helping to build the Chainers universe together, with users showing unbounded creativity and great collaborative efforts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="3341" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/12/23/chainers-review/fkrbknlwiaaknh2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/FkrBKnLWIAAKNH2.jpeg?fit=1200%2C750&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1200,750" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="FkrBKnLWIAAKNH2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/FkrBKnLWIAAKNH2.jpeg?fit=300%2C188&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/FkrBKnLWIAAKNH2.jpeg?fit=1024%2C640&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="640" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/FkrBKnLWIAAKNH2.jpeg?resize=1024%2C640&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3341"  sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Chainers announced a free NFT distribution campaign</figcaption></figure>



<p>To promote the platform’s official launch, Chainers is running a <a href="https://chainers.io/free-nfts?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=nft&amp;utm_campaign=gamefi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">free NFT campaign</a> that gives community members access to limited edition NFTs on the Chainers website and through social media channels. Every Chainers Hero NFT is a playable character in the demonstration version currently on offer, and will be playable in the final full release, with all collected NFTs also being transferable. This gives early players a big advantage when it comes to the full game deployment, not only in the game itself but also in the marketplace – these free NFTs could prove very valuable when the game is well established and certain NFTs are highly sought after.</p>



<p>Chainers players start the game with a basic Chainers Hero and are gifted two random NFTs to start them off. Then, by simply entering the website, they are rewarded with a free NFT every day –&nbsp; one day they might get a t-shirt, the next day a funny hat. There are more than 1,000 unique NFT items to be collected, as well as 15 Chainer races to discover. </p>



<p>There are also 100+ levels of NFT progression, so the fun and exploration never stops. The Chainers team will also provide an Augmented Reality (AR) mode for each NFT, allowing players to interact with their NFT Heros and create a wealth of user-generated content.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;Chainers ecosystem&nbsp;offers several key features, including free-to-play massively multiplayer online (MMO) games that can be accessed from any browser without the need for downloads, immersive and engaging gameplay and mechanics that allow players to monetize their participation in the metaverse. These games allow thousands of players to access and play in the same virtual world simultaneously, featuring engaging storylines and advanced customization options. Chainers also shares a significant portion of the platform’s revenue with the community, allowing the project to work towards a more decentralised gaming space.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Chainoooorss <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4e3.png" alt="📣" class="wp-smiley"  /><br>You’ve waited, and you’ll be rewarded <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f381.png" alt="🎁" class="wp-smiley"  /> <br>The <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FreeNFT?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FreeNFT</a> claiming has started <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f389.png" alt="🎉" class="wp-smiley"  /><br><br>So <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GoChainers?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#GoChainers</a> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f449.png" alt="👉" class="wp-smiley"  /> <a href="https://t.co/k0O9Ql0zJs">https://t.co/k0O9Ql0zJs</a> <br>Go and grab your very first <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Chainers?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Chainers</a> and some stuff for them <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f459.png" alt="👙" class="wp-smiley"  /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f9e2.png" alt="🧢" class="wp-smiley"  /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1fa73.png" alt="🩳" class="wp-smiley"  /> <br><br>Share a screenshot of what you got<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley"  /><br>Can’t wait to see <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f924.png" alt="🤤" class="wp-smiley"  /> <a href="https://t.co/3gMGQNyTwN">pic.twitter.com/3gMGQNyTwN</a></p>&mdash; Chainers <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f35f.png" alt="🍟" class="wp-smiley"  /> (@ChainersNFT) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChainersNFT/status/1606308760737153026?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2022</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<h2 id="how-do-i-get-started" class="wp-block-heading">How do I Get Started?</h2>



<p>Getting <a href="https://chainers.io/free-nfts?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=nft&amp;utm_campaign=gamefi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">started with Chainers</a> is easy &#8211; simply head to the website, sign up and you’ll receive your free Chainer and introductory NFTs. Then you can check out your plot of land, start gathering resources and make a home for yourself (and your Chainer!). Once you’ve spent a little time in the Chainers universe, getting around will be child’s play, and soon you’ll be mixing with other Chainers, swapping gossip, and perhaps trading items on the exchange!</p>



<p>There’s a great reason to start your Chainers adventure today &#8211; the team is running a free NFT campaign that rewards new players with exclusive access to limited edition NFTs, in addition to their free starter NFTs. Getting hold of a free daily Chainers NFT is ridiculously easy &#8211; all new players have to do is enter the website on a daily basis and they will be rewarded with something special for their Chainer.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 id="chainers-promises-to-break-the-mould" class="wp-block-heading">Chainers Promises to Break the Mould</h3>



<p>Having addressed the issues that have plagued blockchain games to date, and managed to create a world where NFTs play a crucial role in the playability and growth of the platform, the Chainers team may have struck gold. With a full launch coming in 2023, there’s every chance these pixelated pretenders could turn out to be the genuine article.</p>



<p><strong>Official website</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://chainers.io/free-nfts?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=nft&amp;utm_campaign=gamefi">Chainers.io</a></p>



<p><a href="https://discord.com/invite/chainersnft?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=nft&amp;utm_campaign=gamefi">Discord</a></p>



<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ChainersNFT?utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=nft&amp;utm_campaign=gamefi">Twitter</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/12/23/chainers-review/">Chainers Review &#8211; Free-To-Play NFT Game For Degens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com">NFTandGameFi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>

		<item>
			<title>GameFi Needs To Start Rewarding Players With Bitcoin Rather Than Just NFTs – Here’s Why</title>
			<link>https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/12/17/gamefi-reward-gamers-with-bitcoin/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 14:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
						<dc:creator><![CDATA[NFT and GameFi Team]]></dc:creator>			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://nftandgamefi.com/?p=3304</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s no doubt that Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) are all the rage right now. Many people...]]></description>

			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/shutterstock_2142377323-min.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" /></figure>
<p>There&#8217;s no doubt that <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/02/05/understanding-nfts-everything-you-need-to-know-before-buying/">Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) are</a> all the rage right now. Many people see them as a way to revolutionize the gaming industry and create new possibilities for player interactions. However, a recent study has shown that gamers are actually more interested in earning Bitcoin than NFTs. Here&#8217;s why&#8230;</p>



<ul class="is-style-cnvs-list-styled">
<li><strong>Reason #1 &#8211; Bitcoin Has More Uses</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Unlike NFTs, Bitcoin has a wide range of uses beyond gaming. It can be used to purchase goods and services, pay bills, etc. This makes it much more versatile than NFTs, which are mainly limited to the gaming world. Bitcoin has a higher probability to be useful as a monetary unit account. This means that earning Bitcoin while gaming has the potential to be more profitable <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/11/22/is-nft-dead/">than earning NFTs</a>.</p>



<ul class="is-style-cnvs-list-styled">
<li><strong>Reason #2 &#8211; Bitcoin Is More Stable</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Another reason why gamers are more interested in earning Bitcoin than NFTs is that it&#8217;s much more stable. The value of a single Bitcoin today may not be the same tomorrow, but it&#8217;s far more stable than NFTs. The value of an individual NFT can fluctuate wildly in a very short amount of time, making it difficult to predict its worth.</p>



<ul class="is-style-cnvs-list-styled">
<li><strong>Reason #3 &#8211; Bitcoin Is Easier To Trade</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Bitcoin is also much easier to trade. It&#8217;s fungible. This means that it can be exchanged for other currencies and goods without any problem. On the other hand, NFTs are non-fungible, meaning each one is unique and can only be exchanged with the same type of NFT. This makes trading them much more difficult than Bitcoin.</p>



<h2 id="play-to-earn-incentives-gameplay-but-the-reward-has-to-be-desirable" class="wp-block-heading">Play-To-Earn Incentives Gameplay But The Reward Has To Be Desirable</h2>



<p>Researchers from Zeebedee (Fintech Company) discovered that the majority of respondents (67%) are more likely to play free games if they offer crypto rewards. This is likely because being able to earn rewards for being immersed in a game that is enjoyable rather than working at a job is much more desirable. However, the reward itself must be desirable. Each person has their own way of valuing assets, but it’s clear that Bitcoin is more valuable to gamers <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/02/06/value-of-nfts-how-it-is-formed/">than NFTs</a>.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="3309" data-permalink="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/12/17/gamefi-reward-gamers-with-bitcoin/shutterstock_2181421907-min/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/shutterstock_2181421907-min.jpeg?fit=1000%2C400&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1000,400" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="shutterstock_2181421907-min" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/shutterstock_2181421907-min.jpeg?fit=300%2C120&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/shutterstock_2181421907-min.jpeg?fit=1000%2C400&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="400" src="https://i0.wp.com/nftandgamefi.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/shutterstock_2181421907-min.jpeg?resize=1000%2C400&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3309"  sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>In my opinion, this is because Bitcoin simply has more value because it&#8217;s an asset that&#8217;s backed by energy. Proof of work (or hash rate) is required to mine Bitcoin and it&#8217;s much more difficult to come by than simply collecting NFTs. Gaming requires the trade of your work within a game, so earning a digital asset that corresponds to the energy of that work and has real-world value makes a lot of sense.</p>



<h2 id="freedom-vs-status-bitcoin-vs-nfts" class="wp-block-heading">Freedom vs Status (Bitcoin vs NFTs)</h2>



<p>27% of gamers would be happy if a game offered Bitcoin as a reward. In contrast, only 5% want NFTs as a reward. One speculation is that NFTs, although each individual one is unique, the creators of the game can create a lot of them, potentially leading to inflation. With Bitcoin, there is a finite amount and its value is based on scarcity rather than arbitrary rules set by a game developer.</p>



<p>To illustrate why this could be a problem, imagine that you ranked #1 for a gaming season, but the game developers decided to have a new season every 2 weeks rather than every 4 months.</p>



<p>Eventually, it wouldn’t be worth competing anymore because the rewards are so watered down. This would be like the value of a trophy for a specific competition during a specific time. It has no value beyond the personal recognition of achievement because gamers that buy the NFT would know they didn&#8217;t earn it. This is not an issue with Bitcoin, as it cannot be artificially inflated.</p>



<p>Bitcoin would be like earning prize money and trading that for more time to play and practice rather than work or fund the gamer lifestyle rather than being a status symbol. Although there&#8217;s value in owning status symbols, it seems like more people would opt for the freedom that Bitcoin brings. As sound money can be saved without being devalued due to inflation or manipulated by a central authority, labor can be stored over the long term.</p>



<h2 id="why-not-offer-both" class="wp-block-heading">Why Not Offer Both?</h2>



<p>In the competition, earning trophies is great! But they don&#8217;t create the ability for participants to fully be engaged in the activity. Oftentimes, even the top contenders have to take on side jobs to maintain a living. Prize money helps participants to continue their activity without having to work at jobs they dislike just to continue with this pursuit. BTC can serve this role in digital competitions.</p>



<p>However, it&#8217;s the status symbol of being the &#8216;winner&#8217; that motivates many to excel at that activity. It also unlocks experience and opportunities. Those parading a gold medal often gain more sponsorships and collaborations than those who don&#8217;t. They may even have easier access to events and clubs. As mentioned earlier, this can be likened with NFTs in the digital realm.</p>



<p>This is why offering both Bitcoin and NFTs would be an ideal solution. Each one plays a separate role in creating an industry that both satisfies the human need for resources to survive and the status that drives exciting competition. This duo will create interest within a game and growth in <a href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/05/25/get-started-in-gamefi/">the entire GameFi economy</a>.</p>



<h3 id="final-thoughts" class="wp-block-heading">Final Thoughts</h3>



<p>In conclusion, it&#8217;s clear why gamers are more interested in earning Bitcoin than NFTs. Bitcoin has multiple uses, is more stable, and can be used to fund gaming expenses. NFTs are status symbols, but it is difficult for gamers to earn real-world value from them (beyond influencing sponsorships and other experiences). By offering both Bitcoin and NFTs, game developers can create a system that benefits everyone involved in the gaming industry.</p>



<p>For now, many DeFi games are only offering NFTs as a reward. With these new findings, developers may want to consider adding Bitcoin as a reward option for their games. This will create more opportunities for gamers and could help take the entire GameFi industry to the next level.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com/2022/12/17/gamefi-reward-gamers-with-bitcoin/">GameFi Needs To Start Rewarding Players With Bitcoin Rather Than Just NFTs – Here’s Why</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nftandgamefi.com">NFTandGameFi</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<!-- last GN Pub feeds fetch (not specifically this feed): 2023-08-08 08:58:19 -->
